我想我们得到了它。
I think we got it.
摆
Okay.
在阿斯利开始之前,我只需要五分钟就带你去
Before Asli will start, I will just take five minutes to take you
通过我们一直使用到现在的工作流程
through this workflow that we have been using until now in
(原始内容存档于2019-03-26). Slicer for Fusion 360. 然后阿斯利会带你过去
Slicer for Fusion 360. And then Asli will take you through
2D到3D生成,然后制造的工作流程。
the workflow of 2D to 3D generation, and then fabrication.
我们直接跳进去
So we will jump directly in
教诲,
the tutorial,
我将分享我的屏幕。
and I will share my screen.
还有
And
因此,Slicer for Fusion 360是一个非常容易和直观
so Slicer for Fusion 360 is a very easy and intuitive
程序。 这就是为什么我们一直忠实地使用它,
program. That's why also we have been using it faithfully,
我能说
I can say.
这是一个非常简单的界面。 我只是想告诉你,它接受3D
It is a very easy interface. I just want to tell you, it accepts 3D
像STL和OBJ这样的文件. 当然,它们需要防水。
files like STL and OBJ. Of course, they need to be watertight.
则有四步. 这么说
And it has four steps. So
在这里,你可以看到我的模型打开 和头躺下来。
here you can see my model opens and the head is lying down.
所以,我会再次打开它, 我会选择Z作为一个
So I will open it again, and I will choose Z as an
轴以在正确的轴中正确打开。 对
axis to open it correctly in the correct axis. Yes.
则有四步. 第一步是定义
And it has four steps. The first step is to define
你的激光切割器。 所以你定义了激光切割器
your laser cutter. So you define your laser cutter
用毫米或英寸创建新的制造环境。
by creating a new manufacturing setting in millimeter or inches.
你把尺寸,厚度, 和那些,你可以让他们零。
You put the size, the thickness, and those ones, you can leave them zero.
这是比值。
This is the margin.
一旦你建立了激光切割区域
And then once you have set up your laser cutting area,
你可以留着它。 你可以选择它。
you can save it. You can select it.
因此,你可以在这里看到它已经更新。 这些是我的板子
So you can see down here that it has updated. These are my boards.
这是我材料的厚度。
This is the thickness of my material.
然后,你可以选择 在堆积片,
And then you can choose between stack slices,
你可以选择交叉切片,
you can choose interlock slices,
你可以选择
you can choose
射线片,
radial slices,
和
and
折叠面板.
folded panels.
所以,现在在每个策略中,你
So now in each of the strategies, you
可以定制它们。 如果您选择堆栈切片, 例如您
can customize them. If you choose stack slices, for example, you
在这里可以看到制造的设置,所以你可以直接去激光剪切.
can see here the manufacturing settings, so you can directly go to laser cut.
所以,如果你选择堆叠片,你可以
So if you choose stack slices, you can
改变切片方向,
change the slice direction,
它会自动更新。
and it will automatically update.
你可以修改表单,让它空洞。
You can modify the form and make it hollow.
对不起 你可以看见
Sorry. And you can see
多少钱,
how much,
并适用。 所以会更新
and apply. So it will update
董事会。
the boards.
是吗?
Hmm.
不喜欢这么空洞,我想, 因为我去与鼻子。
It didn't like so hollow, I think, because I went with the nose.
摆
Okay.
好吧,有点不对劲
Okay, there is something wrong.
瓳 而且,我不知道为什么它不做它空洞, 但也会让你看到。
Oh. And also, I don't know why it doesn't do it hollow, but also it will show you.
它做到了,但它没有视觉化。 它有一些虫子。
It did it, but it doesn't visualize it. It has some bugs.
它会告诉你的集合阶梯, 所以你可以走一个
It will show you the assembly steps, so you can go one
一个和
by one and
组装它。
assemble it.
这么说
So
在这里。 它会在纸板上直观
here. It will visualize it in cardboard.
你可以改变,如果你想, 类型切片, 如果有错误,
You can change, if you want, the type of slices, and if there are errors,
它会给你红色。 举个例子,你也可以
it will give you red. And for this one, for example, you can as well
改变切片方向。
change the slice direction.
但你也可以添加
But you can also add
点击更多切片。 你可以移动你的
more by clicking add more slices. You can move your
随处切片.
slices wherever you want.
你可以重新设置和平衡,或者如果你想删除一些。
And you can reset and equalize again, or you can delete some if you want.
那一个会输出。 你可以在这里得到计划。
That one will export. You can get the plans here.
现在红了,但很多时候是红的,但有道理.
Now it's red, but many times it is red, but it makes sense.
你需要看到组装过程来理解它是否有效.
You need to see the assembly process to understand if it will work or not.
有时会因为空心而变红.
Sometimes it makes it red because it's hollow.
你可以在这里选择DXF 以毫米计, 你准备激光切割。
And you can choose here DXF in millimeters, and you're ready to laser cut.
所以这个过程非常简单
So this is very nice and very easy process
使用 Slicer for Fusion 360 从 3D STL 翻译
using the Slicer for Fusion 360 to translate from a 3D STL
或 OBJ, 三维模型, 水密, 到可编织文件
or OBJ, three-dimensional model, watertight, to fabricatable files
直接为激光切割器。 这从我的角度来说,
directly for the laser cutter. And that was from my part,
课程的第一部分。
the first part of the tutorial.
现在Asli可以开始了.
Now Asli can start.
哈罗,大家好。 这是阿斯利。
Hello, everybody. This is Asli.
谢谢你,安娜塔西娅, 介绍斯利切融合。
Thank you, Anastasia, for the introduction to Slicer for Fusion.
我觉得会很好
I think it will be a good
开始,而且我们会回到它 在车间结束时。
start, and also we'll come back to it at the end of the workshop.
Anastasia介绍我时 我是VAAG的
So as Anastasia introduced me, I am from VAAG
在阿姆斯特丹,
in Amsterdam,
从纺织实验室阿姆斯特丹节点。 在VAAG,我们是
from Textile Lab Amsterdam node. And at VAAG, we are
执行名为"文艺复兴"的项目,这是一个伊拉斯谟Plus项目.
executing a project called Renaissance, which is an Erasmus Plus project.
如果你在欧洲,你知道Erasmus Plus的项目。
If you're in Europe, you know Erasmus Plus projects.
这是一个全欧洲
That it is a Europe-wide
教育项目,
project for education,
研究如何开发由人工智能驱动的制造 艺术 设计课程
where we look into developing AI-driven curriculums for manufacturing, art, design,
结构
and architecture
教育。 这仅仅是项目的第一年, 我们正在寻找
educations. And this is just the first year of the project, and we're looking
进到我们可以执行的方法中
into ways where we can implement
作为设计师、艺术家 AI支持的工作流程
AI-supported workflows in our processes as designers, artists,
建筑师. 我是一个建筑师,我有背景
architects. And I am myself an architect, and I have a background in
计算设计,数字设计,以及制造多年.
computational design, digital design, and fabrication for many years.
我也在大学教书
And I also teach at universities
在最初的几年, 但也在制造工作室。
in the first years mostly, but also in fabrication studios.
所以这是课程的简介。 开始吧 直接跳进去
So this is a brief introduction to the course. Let's start. Jump in directly.
首先,我们...
First,
и暗
I did the
在米罗板上展示 这样我就可以和你分享这个链接
presentation in the Miro board so that afterwards I can share the link with you,
然后,你可以轻松地通过它自己, 链接会更容易为
and then you can go through it easily yourself, and the links will be easier for
跟着你 然后我们一起做辅导
you to follow. And then we will do the tutorials together.
让我从这个开始。 我们看看
And let me start with this. So we will look
输入,作为
into, as
Anastasia说,我们在法布学院第二周,所以这个
Anastasia said, we are in the second week of Fab Academy, so this
工作流程被设计为思考 Fab Academy第二周,但它可以是
workflow was designed thinking about the second week of Fab Academy, but it can be
适用于
applied to
显然还有其他的情况和背景。
other situations and contexts, obviously.
但是,因为我们正在做 数字机构, 所以我们正在研究 身体和我们如何
But since we are doing the digital bodies, so we are looking into bodies and how we
可以从中创建2D图像,我们如何从中创建3D模型,然后
can create 2D images out of them, how we can create 3D models out of them, and then
把它们变成激光切割的制造文件。
turn them into fabrication files for laser cutting.
因此,它遵循一个想法 设计制造工作流程,
So it follows an ideation to design to fabrication workflow, and in the
想法,我们将研究准备 2D 图像,我们将使用多模式图像
ideation, we will look into preparing 2D visuals, and we will use multimodal image
生成。 因此,你会使用图像生成在
generation. So you'll use image to image generation in
使用人工智能。 我们将使用文字提示来进一步解释我们想要什么。
Using AI. And we will use text prompts as well to further explain what we want.
然后我们开始准备3D模型。
And then we will move on to preparing 3D models.
在那里,我们将有图像 3D世代再次使用AI,
There we will have image to 3D generation using AI again,
但我们是人类, 人类在循环中是非常重要的。
but we are humans, and human in the loop is really important.
在开始制造我们面对现实世界后果之前
Before we can move on to fabrication where we deal with real world consequences, we
需要检查我们的模型, 我们需要确保 它是实际上我们想要的
need to check our models, and we need to make sure that it is actually what we want
数字化使得一切都成为可能
to make because digital makes everything possible in the
数字世界,但有时在现实世界是不可能实现的.
digital world, but they are not possible sometimes in the real world.
然后,我们将开始准备制造。
And then we will move on to preparation for fabrication.
有,阿纳斯塔西娅说一个选项是切片机,但另一个选项是
And there is, Anastasiia said one option is the slicer, but the other one is
我将介绍一个工作流程,我所遵循的工作流程是,我想制作自己的工具,
I will introduce a workflow that I followed where I looked into making my own tool,
像一个切片机,
like a slicer,
我会告诉你如何使用它 和得到的过程
and I will show you how to use that one and the process of getting to that
使用人工智能。
using AI.
故复说初义.
So let's get back to the beginning.
因此,首先,在我们开始之前,我希望每个人都有机会填写
So first, before we start, I hope everyone had a chance to fill in
训练前调查 这对我的项目,文艺复兴项目很重要.
the pre-training survey. It is important for my project, Renaissance project.
如果你能填写,我真的很感激。
If you were able to fill in, I'm really grateful.
我想给劳拉・穆斯去年的项目 发声
And I would like to give a shout-out to Laura Muth's project from last year from
计算共值周。 她做了一个非常好的项目,所以
the computational couture week. And she did a very nice project, so
当我跟你分享这个联系时 你可以看看她是如何结合的
when I share the link with you, you can have a look at how she combined
图像和
image and
文本到图像工作流程以及图像到3D
text to image workflows and also image to 3D
使用AI进行设计的工作流程.
workflows using AI for design.
因此,让我们开始。
So let's start.
正如阿纳斯塔西娅所说,我们今天将使用Gemini和Tripo.
As Anastasiia said, we will use today Gemini and Tripo.
所以如果你无法
So if you were not able to
下载,或者,对不起,创建一个...
download it or, sorry, create a...
对不起,我想在这里找到我的聊天。 对
Sorry, I'm trying to find my chat here. Yeah.
创建链接。 你可以在这里为Gemini做。 我在聊天时分享了
Create a linkit. You can do it here for Gemini. I shared it in the chat.
还有Tripo 你可以去工作室
And also for Tripo, you can go to studio.tripo.ai
你应当在大地上建立一个账户, 我们将使用免费版本,和
and create an account there. We will use the free versions, and
所以请不要开始使用它们。
so please don't start using them yet.
但如果你想走更多开源
But if you want to go more open source and
显然你可以在当地运行的模型, 如果你有一个
models that you can run locally, obviously, given the fact that if you had a
强大的计算机和图形卡,你可以去 拥抱面,
powerful computer and graphics card, you can go to Hugging Face,
哪个
which
就像一个平台 你可以找到不同的
is like a platform where you can find different
制作文本生成、语言翻译、图像生成、视频的模型
models for making text generation, language translation, image generation, video
生成,3D建模. 因此,对于图像生成,你可以使用
generation, 3D modeling. So for image generation, you can use
而不是Gemini或ChatGPT,你可以使用Flux 2,用于
instead of Gemini or ChatGPT, you can use Flux.2, for
例如,或者用于3D建模,可以使用.
example, or for 3D modeling, you can use...
在甚么处. Tradus 2号,抱歉,还有Hunyuan
Where is it? Tradus.2, sorry, or Hunyuan
3D (英语).
3D.
你可以使用它们。 他们网上的信用非常有限,所以你不能用
You can use them. They have very limited credits online, so you cannot use them
完全当您在网上使用它们。 但如果你下载并在当地使用,那么
fully when you use them online. But if you download them and use them locally, then
你可以随便用
you can use them however you like.
所以,让我们搬进来,英寸
So let's move in, in
Gemini。
Gemini.
所以我们有一个
So we have a
像这样的界面,我们可以导入图像,也可以输入
sort of interface like this where we can import images and as well as we can
写出文字。 所以这里重要的是 我总是
write text there. So what is important here is that I always,
以我为例 从最基本的开始
in my example, started with a very basic
做个人类的模特儿 给它一些提示
make human model and gave some prompts to it and
看我能从里面得到什么样的产出
see what kind of outputs I can get out of it.
所以,我会走你 通过一般的即时结构 我使用。
So I will walk you through the general prompt structure that I use.
在这里,不幸的促动变得有点重要。
Here, the prompting unfortunately becomes a little bit important.
所以在这里你可以使用,例如,
So here you can use, for example,
用你的形象,把这个人类人物变成物质。
with your image, transform this human figure into material.
这么说
So
木质
wooden
块,保持姿势不变,不变,镜头角度
blocks, keep the pose same, unchanged, the camera angle
不变,或者你也可以说 改变姿势 这一点,强调表面
unchanged, or you can say also change the pose to this and that, emphasize surface
质量。 所以,你可以说,它将是纹理 或者它可以有关节或
quality. So you can say that it will be textured or it could have joints or
平滑或透明,等等。 也可以说,如果你想要更多的背景。
smooth or transparent, et cetera. And you can also say if you want more background.
让我们来谈谈一些例子。
So let's go through some examples.
这么说
So
你可以在Gemini画的上面画
you can also draw on top of your drawings in Gemini.
所以当我带来
So when I bring in
像这样的形象,我说... 对不起
an image like this and I say... Sorry,
用这个
just use this.
也可以点击你的模型,然后对它进行草图绘制.
You can also click on your model and then sketch on it.
这就是我用过的。
So this is what I used.
我现在就留着它
I'm going to save it for now
然后回到这,然后你打 明显的屈服,然后它
and get back to this, and then you hit obviously submit, and then it
将开始创建。 我用Gemini做这个的原因是 你有更多的
will start creating. The reason that I use Gemini for this is that you have more
免费信用,与Gemini一起进行图像生成的日常信用.
free credits, daily credits with Gemini for image generation.
但是,ChatGPT不喜欢裸体的人,虽然
But also, ChatGPT does not like nude people, although
他们是
they are
3D数码. 还有
3D digital. And
所以它不能超越它的护栏,
so it cannot go beyond its guardrails, and
即使你试图说服它, 它不允许你创造改变,
even though you try to convince it, it doesn't allow you to create alterations,
对裸体的修改
modifications on nude bodies.
所以,如你所见,
So as you see,
它产生了
it generated
图像,然后可以下载和使用。
an image to the image that I can then download and use.
但正如我所说,你也可以研究不同的材料
But as I said, you can also look into different kind of material
质量或
qualities or
身体的分解,也包括更重要的
defragmentations of the body and also include more important
有关其建筑的资料,如关节和毛巾等等,或
information about its construction, like joints and dowels and whatnot, or
创造不同的结构 和更多的自然结构围绕它,
create different kind of structures and more natural structures around it and
把它伸到身体本身之外一点
extend it a little bit beyond the body itself.
或像这个例子,你也可以吸它
Or like this example, you can also voxelate it
为了能用我想要的尺度 来吸吸它,我
and to be able to voxelate it in the scale that I want, I
给人高度,然后给人数量
gave the human height and then gave the number of
体素化，
voxelation,
阴极立方体的大小。 Voxelation 就像是像素,但是在
the size of the voxelation cubes. Voxelation is like pixels but in
三维. 因此像素在两个维度中工作,以及
three-dimensional. So pixels work in two dimensions, and
voxels在三个维度工作. 但是在给出这个之前,例如,
voxels work in three dimensions. But before giving this, for example,
它给了我一个Python代码 在那里我可以做到这一点在我的计算机。
it gave me a Python code where I could do this on my computer.
但后来我不得不说,我想要 出现氧化,所以我
But then I had to say that I want the appearance of voxelation, so I
不想实际计算出阴道 并了解那里有多少阴道
do not want to actually compute the voxelation and understand how many voxels there
将会是。 所以它能给我这个输出。
will be. So then it was able to give me this output.
你也可以用姿势来修改身体
You can also modify the body with the pose itself
复制和粘贴身体的部分 再次,它需要一点点
and copy and paste parts of the body Again, it needs a little bit
进一步定义
further definition of
欲作何业. 举例来说,如果你不说, "让他们变形与
what you want to do. And for example, if you do not say, "Make them morph with the
身体",然后它只是复制它, 并把它留在那里, 有时它在前面
body," then it just copies it and leaves it there, and sometimes it's in front of
它,有时它就在它的旁边,但它从来没有与身体的形态.
it, or sometimes it's next to it, but it never morphs with the body.
或者你可以做其他种类的
Or you can do other kinds of
修改或发出不同的提示,
modifications or give different prompts,
可以在身体上创建不同的纹理,也可以完成不同的纹理.
where you can create different textures on the body and also different finishes.
因此,从这里开始,我不仅想
So here, from this point onwards, I wanted to not only
做第一个
do the first
图像生成,但也做一些进一步的修改。
image generation but also do some further modifications on it.
所以,你也可以说,"增加负 凸起的金色," 这意味着
So you can also say, "Increase negative bump in golden colors," which means is that
凸起是一个技术术语 有点在计算机上渲染。
bump is a little bit of a technical term for rendering on computers.
用于3D模型的纹理。
It is for the textures that they apply on the 3D models.
它创造了某种扩展和
It creates sort of an extension and
部分的挤压。 但是如果你有负撞, 这意味着它去
extrusion on parts. But if you have the bump negative, which means that it goes
内向. 所以,这里,当我产生负的冲击,它去
inwards. So here, when I create the negative bump, it goes
下,或者它让 外观下降。
down, or it gives the appearance of going down.
因此,由于这是一个二维图像,它不会做到这一点。
So because this is a 2D image, it will not be able to do that.
所以当你说从这个更平滑的版本增加负凸起时
So you see, when you say increase negative bump from this smoother version, it
继续往深处走
moves on to a little bit deep
裂缝
cracks.
正如我所说,你也可以改变姿势。
You can also change the pose, as I said.
"给人类的啮齿动物 思想家的姿势"
"Give the human rodents the thinker pose."
然后你可以说:"把背景和块块移到人类下面.
And then you can say, "Remove the background and the blocks under the human.
只要保持人类。" 所以你有人类。
Just keep the human." So you have the human.
然后,你也可以融入 转化,要求一些
And then you can also incorporate transformations, ask to make some
转变。 所以我说,"把左脚缩小一半。"
transformations. So I said, "Scale the left foot by half."
然后,你看到脚是微缩的,但它不是
And then you see the foot is slightly scaled, but it's not
完全一半的原尺寸。
exactly half of the original size.
所以,这意味着你可以要求 转换命令,因为它是
So what it means is that you can ask for transformation commands because it does
对你说的语义评价. 它不能进行精确的转变。
semantic evaluation of what you said. It cannot do precise transformations.
所以,如果你想做精确的转换, 如切,修剪,选择,和
So if you want to do precise transformations, like cuts, trims, selections, and
准确的界限, 你需要回到你的
exact boundaries, you need to go back to your
Photoshop 或 GIMP 或任何其他图像修改、图像的好旧工具
good old tools of Photoshop or GIMP or any other image alteration, image
修改软件,然后用它,然后把它带到AI更多
modification software you use, and then use it and then bring it to AI for more
解释性转变. 这是另一个失败的例子。
interpretive transformations. So this is another example of where it fails.
所以我说,我把这些点在上面,然后
So I said I put these points on it, and then
我要求用这些作为中心点来创造洞,但
I asked to create holes using these as center points, but
我问了洞
I asked the holes to
但是它无法创造出它们
be same and uniform, but it was not able to create them in
大小一样 你也看到了,它给了我一点点 比我
the same size. And you also see that it gave me a little bit more than what I
问. 我认为它决定 肚脐也需要是
asked for. I think it decided that the belly button also needed to be
空虚了
hollowed out.
或将模型切成红色,
Or slicing the model from where it is indicated with red and
删除手臂、腿和头部,保持身体的纹理,
deleting the arms, legs, and head, keep the texture of the body, make the
背景为白色。 所以,你看,这也 是非常解释性的,它不是
background white. So you see that that is also very interpretive, and it's not
没错
exact.
所以,回去,你可以的,你应该
So going back, you can
考虑加入一些
also think about adding some
纹理你自己
texture yourself by
重叠,
overlapping,
将纹理形象和人类并列
juxtaposing a texture image and the human,
如你所见,然后要求
as you see, and then ask to
缩放纹理,但它没有显示它,但凸起是
scale the texture, but it does not show it, but the bump is
缩放在这里,
scaled here,
如汝所见.
as you see.
再说一遍,
Again,
背景被删除。 光学幻觉作为凸起层应用.
the background is removed. The optical illusion is applied as a bump layer.
这些纹理和凸起层相当重要,因为那样它们就会给
These textures and bump layers are quite important because then they give the
显示
appearance of
非烟雾表面。 所以当你去3D模型生成,
non-smooth surfaces. So when you go to 3D model generation,
他们将在大地上更加明显,
then they will be more apparent in the
您创建的 3D 模型 。
3D model that you create.
或者,这是 一点点睡眠试验 看看我能不能做到这一点。
Or this was a little bit of a sleep trial to see if I could do this.
还有,是的。
And, yeah.
应用轮廓作为纹理. 再次,缩放纹理三次.
Applying the ruffle as a texture. Again, scaling the texture three times.
复次释义. 它试图放大三次,但它并不完全
Again, it's interpretive. It tries to scale it three times, but it's not exactly
3倍大。 3倍大。 它只是更大的。
three times bigger. It's just bigger.
没错
So yeah.
这部分是给
This part is for the
2D影像,我现在就停止分享,问
2D visuals, and I will just stop now sharing and ask
如果你有任何问题或
if you have any questions or if
我们应该开始自己做
we should start making our own
现在的模特儿。 对不起,2D视觉。 对啊
models now. Sorry, 2D visuals. For that, yeah.
你有问题吗?
Do you have any questions?
对 顿 首先,谢谢你的介绍。
Yeah. Hi. So first, thanks for introduction.
还有
And
除了Gemini还有别的选择吗? 你能提醒一下吗?
what was the alternative to Gemini? Could you please remind?
是福禄.
It's Flux.
奢华. 对
Flux. Mm-hmm.
豪华的哈格脸。
Flux on Hugging Face.
还有许多其他选择。
There are many more alternatives.
如果您想要付费版本,也可以使用ChatGPT.
If you want a paid version, you can also use ChatGPT.
正如我所说 它有自己的护栏 所以它不允许你修改
As I said, it has its own guardrail, so it doesn't allow you to even modify a
简单
simple
MakeHuman类的模特,但是是的。
Make Human model, but yeah.
对于这个教程,你希望我们与人类合作, 或者我们也可以与
For this tutorial, you would like that we work with Human, or we can work also with
其他...
other-
随便你做什么都可以 你可以跟他们一起工作
You can work with anything. You can work with
你开始工作, 或者如果你有照片,你可以
what you have started working with, or if you have a photo of yourself, you can
也请它
also ask it to
让他们出现
give them appearance of a
数字设计的身体上没有任何纹理
digitally designed body without any textures on it.
但我会再做一个"创MakeHuman类"
But I will work on the Make Human again.
或者你认为像猫的照片。
Or you think like a photo of a cat.
有可能,对
Could be, yeah.
摆
Okay.
那也是个尸体
That's a body as well.
有一个问题。 是的,我会跟你分享米罗板的链接
And there is a question. Yes, I will share the link to the Miro board with you.
对 还有几个
Oh, yes. There were a few more.
我就跟你分享这个"创MakeHuman类"模型
I will just share this Make Human model with you,
这样,如果您想要从它开始,您就可以下载并使用它。
so that if you want to start with it, you can already download this and use it.
我给你五分钟时间探索
And I will give you maybe five minutes for you to explore the
给自己创造 如果你有问题 我们可以一起调查
generation yourself. And if you have questions, we can look into it together
以免我们在自己探索之前 踏上下一步
so that we don't go to the next step before we look into explore it ourselves.
所以你想让我们去Gemini...
So you would like us to go to the Gemini and-
对
Yes
……试着输入提示词。
... try to put a prompt.
没错
Exactly.
并,是的, 改变的东西。
And to, yeah, to transform something.
是啊,为了改变。 你可以产生一些东西,一件事,和
Yeah, to transform. You can generate a few things, one thing, and
我会的
I will
也许现在分享米罗的链接,以便你看看这些例子
maybe share the Miro link now so that you can look at the examples
在那里,然后
there, and then
他们会帮你的
they will help you.
给你。
There you go.
对不起,快问
Sorry, quick question.
对
Yep.
由汝声闻. 确保我等10秒。 对
By the sound of you. Make sure I wait 10 seconds. Yeah.
你好,弗雷德里克。 - 你好,弗雷德里克。
Hello, Frederick.
哈罗
Hello.
对于初学者来说 有没有比人类容易一点的数字? 故为人.
Is there any figure that is a bit more easy for beginners than a human? So a human.
或者说
Or
我是一个完整的初学者。 我不是设计师 但我想学习
I'm a complete beginner. I'm not a designer, but I want to try to learn the
与大赦国际一起创建模型的步骤。
steps of generating the models with the AI.
正如我所说,我已经把 人类人物在这里聊天,所以你可以
Well, as I said, I already put the human figure in the chat here, so you can
已经下载并上传到Gemini上。 我们正在使用Gemini。
already download it and upload it on Gemini. And we are using Gemini right now.
我将分享我的屏幕,我们将
So I will share my screen, and we will
将我们的数字插入到那里,这个数字是我和你聊天时分享的,然后
insert our figure there, this figure that I shared in the chat with you, and then
我们会写一些提示。 你可以轻易使用米罗板的提示,
we will write some prompts. You can use the prompts from the Miro board easily,
然后我们将产生它。 亚历山德罗,这回答了你的问题吗?
and then we will generate it. So does that answer your question, Alessandro?
对 我会尝试与人类。 所以,我觉得更多的支持 与提示
Yes. I will try with a human then. So I feel a bit more supported with the prompts
米罗板。
of the Miro board.
摆
Okay.
我试试看
I will try that.
摆
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
是的,欢迎。 因为这真的很难 第一次得到Gemini
Yeah, you're welcome. Because that is really difficult the first time to get Gemini
或其他语言模式来做你想做的事。
or any other language model to do what you want.
总是结果 与你想要的有些不同,
And always the results are a little bit different than what you want,
所以这是非常可以理解的。
so that is very understandable.
我能问个问题吗?
Can I ask a question?
对不起,是的。
Sorry, yes.
有人说他们有问题吗?
Did someone say that they have a question?
对 一心奉请. 当你谈论大坝,当你是
Yeah. I'd like to ask a question. When you talked about the damping, when you were
描述图像,你告诉 坝,撞,我们能生成一个
describing the image and you told the damping, the bumping, can we generate an
图像,我们能生成一个人类模型 而不拥有这样的坝?
image, can we generate a human model without not having the damping like this?
因为你说过,我们生成和3D打印后 我们会发现一个碰撞,一个
Because you told that after we generate and we 3D print, we will find a bumping, a
负颠倒. 我们能在Gemini上生成吗? 然后没有
negative bumping. Can we generate on the Gemini and then don't get any
像一个完全粗糙的表面?
damping, like a perfectly rough surface?
当然 对 所以如果你能说我想要一个平滑的表面, 那么它会给
Of course. Yeah. So if you can say that I want a smooth surface, then it will give
你是一个平滑的表面。
you a smooth surface.
对
Oh, yeah.
希望是这样
Hopefully.
摆
Okay.
这并不总是真实的, 但有时这些东西, 这些凸起你创造
It's not always true, but sometimes these things, these bumps that you create on
纹理帮助您生成一个三维效果,一个纹理
the texture helps you with generating a more three-dimensional effect, a texture
在图像到3D模型时,效果。
effect when you go to image to 3D modeling.
瓳
Oh.
这就是为什么我想介绍它, 但如果你不想有任何类型的
That's why I wanted to introduce it, but if you don't want to have any kind of
身体上的额外,你也可以使它非常光滑。
extras on the body, you can also make it very smooth.
对 谢谢
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
对 不用谢
Yeah. You're welcome.
所以问题是,如果Gemini上产生的模型 是完全多元的
So the question is, if the models generated on Gemini are type of fully manifold
对象通常。 这么说
objects usually. So,
我们在Gemini上创建的模型其实不是模型,而是二维图像,所以
the models that we create on Gemini are not actually models, they are 2D images, so
它们还不是流形的。 而我们制作的Tripod,Tripod是
they are not manifold yet. And the ones that we generate on Tripod, Tripod is
通常都不错 如此多元意味着,如果它不是水密的。
usually really good. So manifold means that if it is watertight or not.
这么说
So
如果几何是多面的,那就意味着它是紧水的,然后是3D
if the geometry is manifold, then it means that it's watertight, then it's 3D
可打印。 所以我想解释一下你的问题文本 让其他人
printable. So I'm trying to interpret your question text so that other people
能够理解 通常,这是相当好的。
can understand. And usually it is quite good.
但我们也会去Blender, 我会告诉你两个方法,你可以
But we will also go to Blender, and I'll show you two ways where you can
检查对象是否是多面体或
check if an object is manifold or
Blender能帮助你多变
how Blender can help you make it manifold.
对不起
Sorry.
我的Gemini说,"对不起,我不能产生不安全的图像。" 不知道有没有其他人
My Gemini said, "Sorry, I cannot generate unsafe images." I wonder if other people
管理。 你分享的截图 我...
managed. The screenshot that you shared, I-
你说什么?
Sorry?
没办法
Couldn't.
你能再问一次吗 路易莎?
Can you ask again, Luisa?
对 我把图像,你分享的截图 送到Gemini
Yeah. I sent the image, the screenshot that you shared, into Gemini,
我写了一些迅速, 它说,"对不起,我不能产生不安全的图像。"
and I wrote some prompt, and it said, "Sorry, I can't generate unsafe images."
哦,还有。
Oh, also.
有人驾驭吗?
Did anybody manage?
哦,有趣的是,我们是...
Oh, interesting.
让我找个不裸体的人 因为通常...
Let me find a human that does not look nude, because usually-
这对我来说是有效的。 对不起
It worked for me. Sorry.
是吗?
Hmm?
这对我来说是有效的。
It worked for me.
摆
Okay.
但是,他们展示了一个形象
But they show an image of a
人类与衣服, 我说,"脱掉衣服。"
human with the clothes, and I say, "Take off the clothes."
对
Mm-hmm.
我想看起来像一个娃娃一样。
And I want to look like a doll, like, too.
对
Mm-hmm.
并告诉为什么我要使用它。
And told why I was using it.
聊天时有个问题 你怎么把图像上传给Gemini?
There is a question in the chat. How do you upload the image to Gemini?
摆 我现在就去,希望如此。
Okay. I am going there now, hopefully.
好了 现在我们到了 所以当你去Gemini时
Okay, now we are here. So when you go to Gemini,
您可以点击此选项并上传文件并选择您的
you can either click on this and upload files and select your
从菜单打开的图像, 或者有另一种方式
image from the menu that opens up, or there is another way
把它拖进Gemini
where you drag and drop it into Gemini.
然后在这里你写自己的
And then here you write your own
电源。 比如说
prompts. And for example,
我可以再带一个
I can bring another
快点
prompt.
呜呼。
Whoop.
因此,将这个数字变成一个由半透明塑料制成的软,充气的体.
So turn the figure into a soft, inflatable body made from semi-transparent plastic.
不见内道.
I don't want to see the interiors.
这么说
So
然后,我们可以进一步说, "删除
then we can further say, "Remove the
背景情况
background
并创造右手,
and make the right hand
"比左手还大"
bigger than the left hand."
所以,你需要进一步的修改 因为现在它显示的手。
So you need further modifications because now it shows the hand.
你可以回到这里,然后点击“编辑提示”,使右手比“编辑提示”大。
You can go back here and then click on Edit Prompt, make the right hand bigger than
左边的手,
the left hand,
删除
remove the
原文
original
右手边 让我们看看这是否有效。
right hand. Let's see if this works.
珃
Whoa.
什么事,西华?
Yes, Siva?
对 顿 它还告诉我,它不能产生不安全的图像,
Yes. Hi. It also told me that it can't generate unsafe images,
所以我只是想寻找
so I'm just trying to search for
另一个要尝试的图像 。
another image to try.
摆 我也会寻找...
Okay. I will also search for...
我有一个问题,对不起。
I have a question, sorry.
对
Yeah.
我试图把模型的截图上传到Gemini.
I'm here trying to upload the screenshot of the model to Gemini.
但我不知道为什么我做不到 因为它说它只允许我
But I don't know why I can't do it because it says that it only allows me to
如果我有Gemini的版本,就下载它。
download it if I have the pro version of Gemini.
故不复修习.
So I don't know how to do it again.
所以你需要下载
So you need to download the
亲版?
pro version?
摆 我不知道. 我在Gemini上
Okay. I don't know. I'm on the Gemini.
对
Mm-hmm.
摆
Okay.
每次我试图上传一张照片...
Every time I try to upload a picture...
你能再给我看一次吗 这样我就能知道自己做得对吗?
Can you show me again so I know if I'm doing the right thing?
请 谢谢
Please. Thank you.
没问题
Yeah, no problem.
所以也许
So maybe
我们去
we go to
Gemini。
the Gemini.
对
Mm-hmm.
你在Gemini.google.com/app吗?
Are you here in gemini.google.com/app?
对
Mm-hmm.
你在吗?
Are you there?
我在Gemini上 岂有异体双明.
I was on Gemini. I don't know if there's a different version of Gemini.
摆
Okay.
所以如果你去Gemini.google.com/app - 。
So if you go to gemini.google.com/app-
对
Mm-hmm
. . 这样
... then
在此单击加号并上传文件,然后选择您的
here, click on the plus sign and upload files, and then select your
文件要工作,然后上传到这里。
file that you want to work on, and then upload it here.
然后你可以增加一些事情 你想在这里做,或者
And then you can either add a few things that you want to do here, or
您可以在此写入您的提示以修改它 。
you can write your prompt here to modify it.
或者你也可以从一无所有开始
Or you can also start with nothing.
让我们看看我
And let's see if I
制作一个
make a
状态
standing
人类
human
图
figure
以柔软充气的身体。
with a soft inflatable body.
有趣的是,当你写
The interesting part in this is that when you write
一个文本,
a text,
模型会做什么, LLM会做什么,
what the model will do behind, what the LLM will do,
它将创造出一个形象。
is that it will create an image.
对
Mm-hmm.
所以如果你已经开始给模型一个图像
So if you already start with giving to the model an image,
你已经领先一步了
you're already one step ahead.
对
Mm-hmm.
所以,这就是为什么,例如,我
So that is why, for example, I
无法控制这个人类的比例 但如果我给一个
don't have much control over the proportions of this human, but if I give an
图像输入,然后我有一点点 控制比例,
image input, then I have a little bit more control over the proportions,
姿势,一点点 关于纹理。
the pose, a little bit about the texture as well.
对
Yeah.
我要在聊天时贴上我们看到的两张幻灯片
And I'm going to paste on the chat the two slides that we've seen
数字机构
in the digital bodies
PPT,演示,课...
PPT, the presentation, the class-
对
Mm-hmm
模型的实际运作方式
... of how the model actually works.
我从这里看到非常有趣的例子。
I am seeing very interesting examples from the chat here.
我没有机会看他们。 他们很有趣。
I haven't had a chance to look at them. They're quite interesting.
珃
Wow.
我们是否应该说,我们所有人都可以迈出下一步?
Should we say that we are all good to move to the next step?
对 还有别的问题吗?
Yeah. Are there any other questions?
没有 那么我们绝对可以搬到下一个
No. Then we can definitely move to the next
步骤,这是... 等等,我看看那个
step, which is... Wait, I will just look at that.
对不起
Sorry.
这是...
Which is to-
有问.
There's a question.
有问题吗?
There's a question?
对 空吗?
Yeah. Sora?
空吗?
Sora?
有人举起手来 是的
Somebody raised their hand, yeah.
顿
Hey.
好吧,毫无疑问。
Okay, no question.
摆 但你随时可以阻止我 我喜欢这样
Okay. But you can stop me anytime. I prefer it like that.
否则,感觉就像我看着屏幕时在和虚空说话.
Otherwise, it feels like I'm talking to the void when I'm looking at the screen.
所以如果你现在想要答案 就阻止我吧
So if you feel like you want an answer now, just stop me.
对 接下来是调查Tripod 3D
And yeah. So the next part is looking into Tripod 3D.
你在这里有链接。 我分享了这个链接吗? 我将再次分享这个链接。 呜呼。
You have the link here. Did I share this link? I will share the link again. Whoop.
对不起
Sorry.
所以,请,请,不要使用它 现在,因为如果你现在用这个,
So please, please, please, do not use it now because if you use it now with this,
它会用很多功劳。
it will use a lot of credits.
摆
Okay.
所以在这里,我们将使用Tripod。 Tripo 将图像转换为
So here we will use Tripod. Tripod turns image to
3D型号. 你可以下载 通常,
3D models. You can download them. Usually,
游戏设计师使用这些,
game designers use these,
但像我们这样的人也会使用它。 Tripo德是给你最好的
but people like us also use it. And Tripod is the sort of the best that gives you,
是德克斯问的吗?
as was it Tex who asked it?
最佳解决办法
The best solutions for
三维印刷或制造. 比如Trellis,还有这个免费的
3D printing or fabrication. For example, Trellis, also this free
我一开始建议的 拥抱脸型模型
Hugging Face model that I suggested at the beginning,
也可以创建三维模型,但不能
also can create 3D models, but it does not
立即让你下载一个 SCR 文件 。
immediately let you download an SCR file.
它允许您下载 GLB 文件, 该文件主要用于
It lets you download a GLB file, which is mostly used for
游戏设计,不是捏造. 这是给你的
game design, not fabrication. So this is for you
改为:
to
记得我们该做什么 但我现在就去查
make sure that you remember what we need to do, but I will go through them now on
Tripo德工作室. 在这里,我们点击3D工作空间,然后我们
Tripod Studio. So here, we click on 3D workspace, and then we
有这样的屏幕。
have a screen like this.
给你
There you can use
一个图像
an image
开始。 所以,任何你的照片,你也可以使用它,但你可以
to begin with. So any photo that you have, you can also use it, but you can
使用您制作的照片或模型
use one of the photos or the models that you have made to
开始探索 你上传的照片在这里
start exploring it. And you upload the photo here in
这个角落。
this corner.
我们可以一起选择
We can select it together.
自从
And since
你的。
yours
将会有默认设置, 它会有点不同 。
will have the default settings, it will be slightly different than mine.
一定要把纹理关掉 因为当你把纹理打开时
So make sure that you turn the texture off, because when you turn the texture on,
如你所见 我们用了很多功劳 但为了
as you see, we use a lot of credits. But for
捏造,我们不需要纹理
fabrication, we don't need a texture.
纹理是图像
Texture is the image that is
适用于身体或3D型号之后
applied to the body or a 3D model after
生成地形几何,例如
the topology geometry is created, such as in the
我给你看的小男孩模特儿 但我们不需要纹理来制造
small boy model that I showed you. But we don't need the texture for fabrication,
这样我们就可以关闭它 并节省信用。
so we can turn it off and save on credits.
在地形学方面,三角地形最适合,
And in terms of topology, triangle topology is the most suitable for,
又是编造出来的 所以使用三角比四网.
again, fabrication. So use triangulation rather than quad mesh.
而对于多数,你知道, 或者如你所知,这是相当的
And for the poly count, as you know, or as you might know, it is quite
这很重要 显然,多数越大,通常就越大
important. Obviously, the bigger the poly count is, usually the greater
决议是。 但也意味着
the resolution is. But it also means that
文件大小变得非常大,而且
the file sizes get really big, and
也让
also it makes
当你想之后去制造电脑时 电脑会落后一点
The computer lag a little bit when you want to go to fabrication afterwards,
因为它意味着在模型上有很多点 它需要
because it means that there are a lot of points on the model that it needs to
计算
account for to make the
紧水形.
watertight shape.
但是,低的多聚体意味着你 分辨率少一点,但也许在
But low poly means that then you have a little bit less resolution, but maybe at
我们不是3D打印。
this scale, we are not 3D printing.
我们不是用这个
We are not using this for
游戏设计.
game design.
我们不会把它作为数字资产,这意味着我们将
We are not going to use it as a digital asset, which means that we are going to
用激光切割来编织,这样我们就可以开始
fabricate it with laser cutting, so we can go for
低复数并减少文件大小。
low poly count and decrease our file size.
我给你们看几件东西 比如说,这有点接近
I will just show you a few things. So for example, this has a little bit close
至50万个圆顶,
to 500,000 vertices,
真不错
which is quite nice.
但也许
But maybe
大约有22万个顶点
this has around 220,000 vertices,
这显然比前一个定义少了一点
which is obviously a little bit less defined than the previous
一个 不过,我们做这个不重要
one. But also, it does not matter if we're making this
或用激光切割的碎片编织
out of cardboard or fabricating it with laser-cut pieces.
所以我建议你去
So I would suggest you to go for
可能20万,30万 如果你觉得自己不能
maybe 200,000, 300,000, and if you feel like you cannot
捕获
capture
所有的细节,然后你可以增加它。
all the details, then you can increase it.
但很明显,当你生成一个模型, 然后失去15个
But obviously, when you generate one model, then you lose 15
标志。 所以无论如何, 我想你从200。
tokens. So anyway, and I think you start with 200.
好吧,Tripod的工作原理是 它得到一个
And, okay, how Tripod works is that it gets an
图像,
image,
它的传播模型, 所以它发送光, 然后想象什么后
and it's diffusion modeling, so it sends in light and then imagines what the back
模型看起来是这样。 所以它不知道,但它想象着它。
of the model would look like. So it doesn't know it, but it imagines it.
如果你喜欢,显然, 付费版本, 然后你可以增加更多的观点 在它,
If you go for, obviously, paid versions, then you can add more views into it,
左边 右边 后面 但是,没有付费版本,你没有
left, right, and back. But with the non-paid version, you don't have that
选项。 但如你所见,它并没有做一个真正的坏工作
option. But as you see, it does not do a really bad job
一边想象后面发生了什么
while imagining what's happening at the back.
或者在这里,如果你看看这个,
Or here, if you look at this,
只有这个观点,它才能解释
only having this view, it was able to interpret
它会是什么样子, 而且它不是那么糟糕。
what it would look like, and it's not that bad.
在这里,当我们下来,再次, 它来了最好的
And here, when we come down, again, it comes with the best
质量AI模型,但为了能够下载一个STL文件,您
quality AI model, but to be able to download an STL file, you
需要随心所欲
need to go with in the legacy
AI型号.
AI model.
然后点击生成器,然后启动您的文件或3D模型
Then you hit Generate, and then your file or your 3D model will start
人类的后代。 然后当它做了,
its generation. And then when it's done,
它会出现在这里,
it will appear here,
然后你可以绕着它旋转
and then you can rotate around it
检查一下 例如,这不是一个好的。
and check it. For example, this is not a good one.
也许有50个顶点, 它没有做一个好的工作。
Maybe with 50 vertices, it did not do a good job.
但大约20万
But around 200,000,
没那么糟 然后,一旦你完成了,你打
it's not really that bad. And then once you're done, you hit
导出时,您从列表中选择 STL,以及
Export, you select STL from this list, and
然后导出模型。 这将下载您的
then export the model. This will download your
STL文件到您的计算机。
STL file to your computer.
所以现在
So now
我们可以自己试试看
we can start trying it out ourselves.
所以,如果你去工作室。 Tripo.3d.ai,你可以
So if you go to studio.tripod.3d.ai, you can
从图像中启动您的 3D 世代 。
start your own 3D generations from your images.
如果你需要的话
And if you need
我将再次分享我在这里使用的图像。
an image to begin with, I will again share this image that I was using here.
为了能够记住什么
And to be able to remember what
我用的设置,你可以去米罗板 看看那里的设置。
settings I used, you can go to the Miro board and look at the settings there.
同时,我可以回答一些问题 如果你有任何问题。
And meanwhile, I can answer some questions if you have any questions.
你能在Tripod再做一次吗? 用聊天的画面之一?
Could you do it again in Tripod with one of the images of the chat?
好吧,让我看看。
Okay, let's see.
和分享屏幕。
And share the screen.
摆
Okay.
现在,
Now,
我已经下载了
I have downloaded
这个
this
型号,
model,
这个
this one,
从聊天。
from the chat.
正如我所说,我们先去一般的设置, 确保纹理关闭。
And as I said, we go to general settings first, make sure that the texture is off.
我们有三角形的地形, 也就是说它创造了三角面孔
We have the triangle topology, which means that it creates triangular faces between
3个顶点,不是网点,是4个
three vertices, not pod mesh, which is four
顶点形成面孔. 礛и蛤
vertices form a face. And then I have, let's go with
30万多元计数,然后
300,000 poly count, and then
下去,确保我们的
go down, make sure that our
AI模型是遗产. 礛
AI model is legacy. And then
让我看看。
let's see.
这里有什么问题吗?
Are there any questions while it is generating my content here?
事实上,是的。 对不起
Actually, yes. Ah, sorry.
对不起 你利用传统模式的原因吗?
Sorry. Is there a reason you're using the legacy model as
与最佳质量或最快和平衡,第三位?
opposed to the best quality or the fastest and balanced, number three?
是的,因为
Yes, because
我有免费的版本。 如果我使用最好的版本, 它不允许我
I have the free version. If I use the best quality version, it doesn't allow me to
下载 STL 模型...
download an STL model-
还好
Okay
...与免费版本。
... with the free version.
谢谢
Thank you.
这就是我拥有的。 也许增加
So this is what I have. Maybe increasing
复数会给我更好的定义
the poly count would have given me better definition.
所以也许也试试看
So maybe let's try that one as well.
输出时, 输出到哪里 ?
When you export it, where do you export it to?
有不同的方式 你可以输出它,我可以看到。
There's different ways you can export it, I can see.
在这里,你选择STL,然后
So this here, you select the STL, and then
对不起 这是一个四面体模型,所以它不允许我下载。
Sorry. This was a quad model, so it doesn't allow me to download that one.
所以,你输出它,
So you export it,
然后它只是下载STL。
and then it just downloads the STL.
你看到不同的行为了吗,蒂娜? 是你问的吗?
Do you see a different behavior, Tina? Was it you who asked the question?
对不起 没事 没事 它的工作原理。
Sorry. Yeah, no, it's fine. It works.
这只是...
It was just the-
有用吗?
It works
...下一部分被送到Blender等等。 所以,只是想知道。 问。
... next part that was sent to Blender, et cetera. So just wondering.
不过是的,我明白了。
But yeah, I see.
对
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
不用谢
You're welcome.
没错 现在,这个
So yeah. Now this has
更多定义
more definition
对它比前一个。
to it than the previous one.
但我必须说天平
But I must say that the scales on
联合国
the
鱼部位有一点失落,这种尺度效应。
fish part is a little bit lost, that scale effect.
还有别的问题吗?
Are there any other questions?
是的,我有一个问题。 当我上传我的
Yes, I have a question. When I have uploaded my
模型到工作空间,它现在被淡化了。
model to the workspace, it is now dimmed out.
整个左面板
The whole left panel
现在有点稀释了 我可以看到我上传到
is now sort of dimmed out. I can see the model that I've uploaded onto the
工作空间,但我无法访问 任何东西,任何设置或任何进一步。
workspace, but I can't access anything, any settings or anything further.
左边?
On the left?
对 你知道当你上传你的图像...
Yes. You know when you upload your image-
对
Mm-hmm
放在屏幕左侧的面板上
... it's gone into a panel on the left-hand side of the screen.
对
Yep.
所以现在整个面板都变暗或灰了,
So now that entire panel has become dimmed or grayed out,
所以我无法使用它。 我做错什么了吗?
so I can't use it. Have I done something wrong?
我带来了一个JPEG, 也许它必须是PNG?
I brought in a JPEG, maybe it had to be a PNG?
不,它也支持JPEG,所以它不应该是问题。
No, it supports JPEG as well, so it should not be the problem.
摆
Okay.
我该送你过去吗? 也许你...
But shall I walk you through it? Maybe you-
当然
Sure.
是啊,所以在这里,你也可以, 而不是把它在这里,你可以
Yeah, so here, you can also, instead of dropping it here, you can
选择此框或单击此框
select this box or click on this box
并随后
and then
选择一个图像。
select an image.
让我选择一个JPEG。
Let me select a JPEG.
其他相当... 摆
Other quite... Okay.
正如你所见,它是一个JPEG。
As you see, it's a JPEG.
对
Yeah.
并且它上传无问题。
And it uploads without a problem.
也许是我选的照片 我会尝试一个不同的图像。
Maybe it's the image I selected. I'll try a different image.
摆
Okay.
还有,抱歉,我想我需要帮助
Also, sorry, I need some help, I think.
对
Yeah.
如果我分享我的屏幕,好吗? 因为我不能输出我的模型?
Is that okay if I share my screen, because I cannot export my model?
对 对
Yes. Mm-hmm.
所以说
So I
创建了HD模型.
created a HD model.
对
Mm-hmm.
我删除了纹理,所以减少, 和多计数是
I removed the texture, so to reduce, and the poly count is
好吧,在这里。
okay right here.
对
Mm-hmm.
还是我应该少一点?
Or should I make it less?
不,但我知道你有四大地形,不是网状
No, but I see that you have a quad topology, not a mesh
三角地形学.
triangular topology.
对不起,我该怎么办?
Sorry, what should I do?
现在你选择了三角形 但在这个模型中 你没有...
Now you have the triangle selected, but in this model, you did not have the...
我可以给你看我的屏幕,
Can I show you my screen,
路易莎吗?
Luiza?
对
Mm-hmm.
摆
Okay.
所以,如你所见,这里是四角。 这是一个四面体地形。
So this, as you see, says quad here. It is a quad topology.
哦,不是三角形的。 摆 不一样 但我会试着找到的 对
Oh, not triangle. Okay. Not really the same, but I will try to find it. Uh-huh.
好吧,所以与四, 它是可能的输出,对不对?
Okay, so with quad, it's possible to export, right?
无法出口STL. 你看,它不允许我出口
It's not possible to export STL. As you see, it doesn't allow me to export
STL带四。
STL with quad.
对
Mm-hmm.
所以,你需要做的是 你需要再生 你的模型,但使用三角形
So what you need to do is you need to regenerate your model, but using the triangle
地形学而不是四层地形学.
topology rather than the quad topology.
摆
Okay.
做到这一点,在你选择四边形或三角形后,你需要
Do that, and after you select quad or triangle, you need to
重击生成。
hit Generate again.
有没有出口的方法?
And is there a way to export it?
生成模型后...
After you generate the model-
对
Mm-hmm
三角形的地貌,可以把它导出
... with triangle topology, then it will allow you to export it as an
(原始内容存档于2017-09-21). StL.
STL.
对
Mm-hmm.
再次分享你的屏幕 让我可以跟着。
Share your screen again so that I can follow along.
对 我的其实是一个三角形, 它已经在一个
Yes. Mine actually was a triangle, and it was already in a
库拉的三角形,
triangle in Cura,
和
and
H 2.5,就像你说的。 我删除了纹理。
H 2.5, as you said. And I removed the texture.
而多点数现在非常低。 可以吗?
And poly count is very low now. Is it okay?
我是说...
Or, I mean-
让我们看看。 我觉得那不会对...
Let's see. I don't think that that would have an effect on the-
摆
Okay.
也许我可以停止分享。 我的意思是,这只是 因为我不想采取很多
Maybe I can stop share. I mean, it's just because I don't want to take a lot of
时间。 我的意思是,一开始, 它已经三角,所以
time. I mean, at the beginning, it was already triangular, so
我不知道为什么它不允许。 所以,也许我现在可以停止, 你可以继续,
I don't know why it didn't allow. So maybe I can stop now, you can continue, and
那么这是
then it's
生成。 我还可以再分享一次
generated. I can share again.
摆 因为你想...
Okay. Because you want to-
瓳 现在尝试导出它。 今在此处.
Oh. Now try to export it. It's here now.
对 等等,我不喜欢的东西。
Mm-hmm. Wait, I don't like things.
此处导出为紫色按钮 。
Export is the purple button here.
对不起
Oh, sorry.
这里。
Here.
现在我明白了。 对
Now I see. Mm-hmm.
哦,这是很好的。 可能是因为...
Oh, it's good. So probably it was because it had
电网。 是啊,这就是原因。 摆
grids. Yeah, that's why. Okay.
可能是一个四面体模型。 你能回到前一个吗?
It was a quad model probably. Can you go back to the previous one?
你给我看的那个...
The one that you showed me that was a-
可能是这个
It's probably this one.
这个 对
This. Mm-hmm.
对 看这里。 你会吗?
Yes. Look here. Do you
看到没? 上面说地形是四重奏
see? It says the topology was quad.
哦,没关系。
Oh, okay.
好吗?
Okay?
摆 非常感谢
Okay. Thank you so much.
没问题
No problem.
好吧,还有问题吗?
Okay, any more questions?
现在我们可以直接打印3D了吗?
So now we can 3D print it directly?
我的意思是,是的,也许。 你需要把它带到你的切片软件。
I mean, yes, maybe. You need to take it to your slicer software.
幻觉... 对不起 棱镜工很擅长修复
Fusion... Sorry. PrusaSlicers are quite good at mending the
差距,所以它不应该是一个问题,而是对我们
gaps, so it should not be a problem, but for our
自己来,我不知道。
own sake, I don't know.
这也是如果它非常重,你可以使它在Blender非常轻.
It's also that if it is very heavy, you can make it very light in Blender.
对
Yes.
Mm.
所以现在...
So for now...
瓳
Oh.
歌手,你的模特儿出来了
Singer, your model came out quite nice.
摆
Okay.
对 总之
Yeah. So anyway.
Janek,你想分享你的屏幕 这样我们就可以一起翻阅
Janek, do you want to share your screen so that we can go over it together
也许?
maybe?
好吧,我会试试。
Okay, I'll try it.
и琌
I'm
只是通过两个屏幕工作。 忍着点
just working across two screens. Bear with me.
没问题
No problem.
你能看到我的屏幕了吗?
Can you see my screen now?
是的 但我没看到... 哦,我看到了图像。
Yes, but I don't see the... Oh, I see the image.
则阴虚之光. 这是我尝试过的第二个形象.
And it's dim light. That's the second image I've tried.
是哪个画面? 那个
Which image is it? The
经营女人?
running woman?
是的,是那个跑步的女人 上一个只是西班牙舞者 穿着红色
Yeah, it's the running woman. The previous one was just a Spanish dancer in a red
装束
outfit.
我想,也许有太多 弹出的材料, 所以我只是尝试运行
I thought maybe there were too many flounces of material, so I just tried a running
图像。
image.
不过,我...
Well, still, I
想象一个有面具的图像
think a masked image which has a
简单的背景会更好。
simple background would work better.
摆
Okay.
我觉得这里很难区分什么是
I think here it is having a hard time differentiating what is in the
前面和后面的东西 这可能是原因。
front and what's in the back. That could be the reason.
摆
Okay.
是啊,所以简单的背景工作更好。
Yeah, so simple backgrounds work better.
摆 我再来一次 谢谢
Okay. I'll give it another go. Thank you.
是的,欢迎。
Yeah, you're welcome.
我还想... 诺埃尔,是吗?
I also wanted to... Noel, yeah?
对
Yep.
对 顿
Yeah. Hi.
顿
Hi.
我生成了.STL文件,
I generated the .STL file,
我用其他软件打开它,叫做自由CAD, 我可以看到
and I opened it in other software called Free CAD, and I could see
3D型号. 所以,只是一个问题,我可以
the 3D model. So just a question, can I
使用此模型打印 3D 吗 ?
use this model for a 3D printing?
对
Yeah.
摆
Okay.
检查尺寸,不过,因为它们相当小。
Check the sizes, though, because they are quite tiny.
它使用一个单位作为高度,和一个单位在
It uses one unit as height, and one unit in
3D打印软件通常使用毫米作为世界这边的单位,
3D printing software usually uses millimeters as units in this side of the world,
这意味着它会像一毫米高。
which means that it comes as one millimeter high.
所以你需要调整你的模型大小。
So you need to resize your models.
摆 我是三维模型和三维打印器的新手
Okay. I'm new to the 3D model and 3D printing.
所以我才刚刚想出来
So I'm just figuring out.
对
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
没问题 只是缩小范围会是一个问题。
Yes, no problem. Just sizing will be an issue.
当然 对
Sure. Yeah.
对 我还想谈谈目前的情况。
Yes. I would also like to share that currently
Tripo有比赛
there is a competition on Tripo. I
已经把它放在聊天。 它被称为特里帕森。
have put it in the chat. It is called the Tripathon.
它已经打开了,直到
And it is open already, and until the
10月5号,
October 5th,
您可以提交您的项目。 这是
you can submit your projects. And it is
也有一些巡回表演日,
also having some tour open demo days,
我会把位置。 我想在巴塞罗那,
and I will put the locations. I think in Barcelona,
这是在
it's on the
10月17日 (中文(简体) ).
17th of October
在巴塞罗那。
in Barcelona.
如果你是的话
So if you are
现在迷上了Tripo,你可以
fascinated now with Tripo, you can
参加比赛。 我会是陪审团,所以
participate in the competition. And I will be jury, so
我可以投给你。
I can vote for you.
对
Yes.
因此,有一个Discord社区, 和事件,你可以发现他们上
So there is this Discord community, and the events, you can find them on the
链接。
link.
在线参与.
Online participation.
对不起,我能问一个关于比赛的问题吗?
Sorry, can I ask a question about the competition?
我不太明白你说什么 我看见了联系,但我不明白是什么
I don't really understand. I saw the link, but I don't really understand what's the
有关项目。 我们要提交什么?
project about. What do we have to submit?
你的创造 任何东西。
Your creations. Anything.
有发现吗?
Anything?
最疯狂的事 你没有简报。
The craziest things. You don't have a brief.
这是利用工具 来制造
It's the use of the tool for being able to make an
STL 3D网格模型,不是吗?
STL 3D mesh model, no?
我想如果你看着
I think if you look at the
Tripo登陆网页 主页 有很多例子
Tripo landing page, the homepage, there's a lot of examples there
来刺激你的想象力 但人们正在做很多不同的事情
to sort of fuel your imagination. But people are doing a lot of different things
用这个
with it.
但这是登陆页?
But that's on the landing page?
是的,在网页上。
Yeah, on the webpage.
摆
Okay.
只是滚动下来。 人们已经做了很多例子。
Just scroll down. There's tons of examples that people have done.
摆
Okay.
我也有一个问题 关于生成的模型。
I also have a question regarding the generated model.
对
Yeah.
我试图下载,但我不知道
I tried to download it, but I don't know which
因为下载的正常版本是
format should I download it with, because the downloaded normal version is
我不知道你们怎么下载的
paid, so I don't know how you guys are downloading it.
这么说
So
时
while
生成模型...
generating the model-
对
Mm-hmm
……
...
在生成模型的同时 你需要从左手边下去
while generating the model, you need to go down here on the left-hand side and
选择
select
H2.5 遗产.
H 2.5 Legacy.
哦,让我看看,如果我找到它。
Oh, let me see if I find it.
对
Yeah.
因为默认情况下,它与H 3.1, 和免费版本,
Because by default, it comes with H 3.1, and with the free version,
不允许下载 STL 文件。
you're not allowed to download an STL file.
摆
Okay.
所以你需要选择遗产模型。
So you need to select the legacy model.
我想我失去了我的生成模型。 我不知道现在在哪里
I think I lost my generated model. I don't know where it is now.
好吧,你要去再生 模型,所以没关系。
Well, you're going to regenerate the model again, so it doesn't matter.
摆
Okay.
因为你需要用这个模型从图像中重新生成它,这个AI
Because you need to regenerate it from an image again using this model, this AI
型号。 不是这个三维模型 我说的是人工智能模型
model. Not this 3D model. I'm talking about this AI model.
所以,我...
So I...
所以再上传一个图像。 确定您的纹理
So upload an image again. Make sure that you have the texture of
三角形地形和任意多边形。
triangle topology and any polygons that you want.
摆
Okay.
然后向下滚动
And then scroll down
并选择 H 2.5 遗产
and select H 2.5 Legacy
在大赦国际模式下,
under AI model,
然后击中生成。
and then hit Generate.
所以我点击...
So I click...
你能再次分享你的屏幕吗?
Could you share your screen again?
对 摆 因为我认为我失去了我创造的另一个模型,或者
Yeah. Okay. Because I think I lost the other model that I created, or
没有 摆
no. Okay.
对 你知道为什么吗?
Yeah. You know why?
因为模型是用3.0生成的.
Because the model was generated with a 3.0.
对
Yeah.
所以当你选择2.5时,它需要再次再生.
So when you choose the 2.5, it needs to regenerate again.
对
Mm-hmm.
你能分享吗? 对
Can you share it? Yeah.
共'.
It's shared.
我们看见了吗? 我不知道.
Are we seeing this? I don't know.
你能看见...
Can you see the-
是的,我们可以看到。
Yes, we can see.
摆 所以,好吧,我想我是在这里。
Okay. So, okay, I think I was going here.
是的,上传。
Yeah, upload.
这里?
Here?
对
Yeah.
但是,你用 - ,
But are you using-
但上传前请选择2.5
But before you upload, choose the 2.5
或者当你上传,选择2.5。
Or as soon as you upload, choose the 2.5.
我得先上传?
So I have to upload it first?
先上传图像.
Upload the image first.
摆
Okay.
你在用Tripo吗?
Are you using Tripo?
那个...
Uh...
你在用棱镜3.1
You're using Prism 3.1.
是啊,这是另一个。 Tripo来了,明白吗?
Yeah, it's the other one. Tripo is here, you see?
对
Mm-hmm.
这里。
Here.
不,等等,别这样 对不起
No, wait. Sorry.
哦,Tripo,伙计们。 对不起 Tripo在这里。 摆 上传? 对
Oh, Tripo, guys. Sorry. Tripo here. Okay. Upload? Right.
摆
Okay.
我要试试这个
I'm just going to try this one.
这么说
So
我现在在哪里点击它? 我只是先生成它, 还是我必须点击什么地方?
where do I click it now? I just generate it first, or do I have to click somewhere?
那个
Well,
我不知道. 我从没用过这个接口,所以...
I don't know. I've never used this interface, so-
上来吧
Go up.
我会...
I'll just-
去一点点。 卷起来
Go a little bit. Scroll up.
犹如P2. 您可以单击所有模型或
It's like P2. Can you click All Models or
上面写了什么,是的,游戏准备好了?
what it says there, yeah, Game Ready?
对 没有
Yeah. No.
哪个?
Which?
不,这是正确的一个。
No, it's the correct one.
对
Yeah.
是这个吗?
It's this one?
但上面写着"原生的四方输出",所以不是这个.
But it says Native Quad Output, so it's not this one.
没有 继续...
No. Go to-
你使用从工作室。
You're using from the studio.tripo.3d.
摆
Okay.
我认为你在使用Git 和另一个LLM模型相连
I think you're using Git linked to another LLM model.
哦,我用错了链接?
Oh, I'm using the wrong link?
这是你的账户 在Tripo?
It is your account in Tripo?
是吗?
Hmm.
我不知道 我刚刚点击了这里谈话的链接 и琌...
I don't know, I just clicked the link from the conversation here. I just...
我不知道.
I don't know.
怪怪的。 怪怪的。
Weird.
没有 我不知道. 所以它只是一个不同的Tripo?
No. I don't know. So it's just a different Tripo?
我不知道.
I don't know.
你有没有点击这个链接?
Did you click this link?
你能再次发送链接 所以我 -
Can you send the link again so I-
对
Yeah
确保它是正确的吗?
... make sure it's the right one?
因为似乎你下载了一些 有很多不同的模型。
Because it seems that you downloaded something that has many different models.
对
Yeah.
哦,我不知道,我还不知道
Oh, I don't know.
我们实际上想知道是什么。
We would like actually to know what it is.
我不知道.
I don't know.
叫什么来着?
What is the name?
腾讯网站.
It's the website.
哦,我不知道,我还不知道 是这个
Oh, I don't know. It's this one.
我不知道.
I don't know.
不过好,我现在就去 摆
But okay, I'm going here now. Okay.
对
Mm-hmm.
所以我必须先登录,对吧?
So I have to log in first, right?
对
Yes.
摆
Okay.
我们没看到你的屏幕 但我们不需要看到它
Well, we don't see your screen, but we don't need to see it.
我们看到前一个屏幕。
We see the previous screen.
哦,你看到之前的屏幕了吗?
Oh, you see the previous screen?
对 我们不需要看到你的屏幕 当你做它。
Yeah. We don't need to see your screen while you're making it.
对 你可以探索STL
Yes, you can explore STL.
对
Mm-hmm.
摆 这给了我很多选择 我点击3D印象,对不对?
Okay. This gives me a lot of options to do. I click in the 3D impression, right?
没有
No.
3D印象吗?
3D impression?
对 让我看看能不能
Yeah. Let me see if I can
份额
share
作么生会.
what I'm doing.
你看到了吗? 我在这里。
Are you seeing this? I'm here.
是的,你必须...
Yeah, you need to-
我还在这里
I'm still here
...从这个盒子外的某个地方点击
... click out of this box, somewhere outside of this box.
但它只是在这里。 我不知道.
But it just went here. I don't know.
摆 点击
Okay. Click on
三维打印机.
3D printer.
我觉得... 是啊,给你。 在这个阶段,它正在问你 什么样的
I think it... Yeah, there you go. At this stage, it's asking you what kind of
设计要做的事。
designing you want to do.
对
Yeah.
还有
And
函数对象。 是啊,功能对象。
functional objects. Yeah, functional objects.
像这样还是不行?
Like this or no?
选择任何东西。 没关系
Select anything. It doesn't matter.
摆 没关系
Okay. It doesn't matter.
对
Yes.
所以我要点击一个开始。
So I'm just going to click Create a Start.
然后埃斯帕西奥3D。 选择左上角的那个
And then Espacio 3D. Select that one on the left upper corner.
瓳
Oh.
在Tripo旁边 对 没有
Next to Tripo. Yeah. No.
模特儿吗?
Model?
对 现在你和我们一样在屏幕上
Yeah. Now you're in the same screen as us.
瓳
Oh.
不错
Great.
摆 现在,我只是生成它, 还是我点击的地方先?
Okay. Now I just generate it, or I click somewhere first?
首先,你需要上传你的图像,然后,是的。
First, you need to upload your image, and then, yes.
你看,现在你有 遗产模型。
You see, now you have the legacy model.
摆
Okay.
你能够做到。
You were able to.
Gemini。
Gemini.
但是在你尝试的时候,我们还能继续吗?
But shall we continue while you're trying this out?
对 谢谢 对不起 谢谢
Yeah. Thank you. Sorry. Thank you.
不用谢 没问题
You're welcome. No problem.
我不介意我还分享屏幕 如果没关系。
I don't mind if I'm still sharing the screen if it's okay.
没关系。
It's okay.
我只是想说一些关于图像。
I just wanted to also say something regarding the images.
我在聊天时分享了模型是如何工作的, LLM是如何工作的
I shared in the chat at some point how the model works, how the LLM
生成文件,你会看到有两种方法。
generates the file, and you will see that there are two ways.
那一个,基本上它创造了不同的观点
That the one, basically it creates different views
,然后将其编成三维模型或
of the picture, and then it composes them to a 3D model or the
传播. 基本上有两个不同的算法.
diffusion. There are two different algorithms, basically.
或者另一个是它制造噪音,然后去除噪音。
Or the other one is that it makes noise and then it de-noises.
所以,这意味着,如果你想 做更精确的东西,它
So this means that if you want to make something more precise, it
如果你有更多的图片输入会更好。
is better if you have input more pictures.
譬如放顶,侧,前,后.
Like if you put the top, the side, the front, and the back.
但这种
But this kind of
计算,它有一个问题,你看到很多次你有很多
calculation, it has this problem that you see many times that you have many
手指,比如说。
fingers, for example.
这叫雅努斯问题
This is called the Janus problem.
但它总是更好 因为LLM是这样工作的, 如果你已经想要
But it's always better because the LLM works like that, that if you already want to
做一个技术设计, 你提供不同的观点。 这是一个括号。
do a technical design, you provide the different views. That's a parenthesis.
对不起,阿斯利
Sorry, Asli.
没问题 但是在自由阶梯中也不允许你输入
No problem. But it's also not allowed in the free tier that you cannot input
多视. 所以,现在,它不是
multi-view. So at this point, it's not
对我们来说是可能的,但是如果你想要更精确,你就能知道
possible for us, but it's good to know that if you want more precision and you
想要吗?
want to
准确输入背后和侧面的情况,而不是
give the input of what's happening at the back and on the sides precisely, and not
让Tripo或其他任何3D模型生成器想象一下
let the Tripo or any other 3D model generator imagine it
然后,你需要表达不同的观点 这样你就可以更好地控制
itself, then you need to give different views so that you are more in control of
物体周围发生的一切,360。 没错
what's happening all around the object, 360. That's true.
所以,让我们继续
So let's continue with
Blender有点。 这么说
Blender a little bit. So
你们都有他们可以使用的STL文件吗?
do all of you have a sort of STL file that they can work with?
不错
Great.
我们先休息,再休息?
Shall we take a break first, bio break first?
我觉得,然后...
I think, and then-
音乐生化休息,五分钟。
Musical bio break, five minutes.
在重新开始之前,马基又对STL文件提出疑问
Before we start again, Maki has a question again about STL file
导出。
export.
正如阿纳斯塔西娅所言 在你创造你的遗产之前
You need to choose legacy, as Anastasiia put there, before you generate your
型号。 如果你去米罗板,你可以看到
model. And if you go to the Miro board, you can see
怎样才能做到呢? 因此,你需要这样做 在你再次生成模型之前。
how you can do it. So you need to do this before you generate the model again.
所以你上传你的图像 然后选择遗产2.5,
So you upload your image, and then you choose the Legacy 2.5,
然后生成模型。
and then generate the model.
对 哈罗
Yes. Hello.
对
Yeah.
我选择了遗产2.5 它做到了。
I chose Legacy 2.5 and it made it.
对
Mm-hmm.
然后我试图出口
And then I tried to export
这个
it.
对
Mm-hmm.
我试图选择发送到Blender。
And I tried to choose send to Blender.
不是发到Blender。 你必须...
Not send to Blender. You need to-
哦,没关系。 只是出口吗?
Oh, okay. Just export?
对,出口
Yeah, export.
哦,没关系。
Oh, okay.
选择STL和导出 。
Choose STL and export.
而纹理分辨率是4K是罚款?
And the texture resolution is 4K is fine?
对 那个...
Right. The-
4K型车.
4K.
有几个...
There is several-
纹理.
Texture.
是啊,有好几个
Yeah, there is several
纹理分辨率选择。
selections for texture resolution.
所以说...
So-
但我们没有使用纹理,因为...
But we are not using texture because-
还好
Okay
...我们要编造它。 如果你想用纹理 那就用
... we're going to fabricate it. Well, if you want to use texture, then you use
更多的符号,然后你有图像 -
more tokens, then you have the image-
摆 这么说吧...
Okay. So just-
...缠绕着
... wrapped around
...推进。
... push the import.
是的,但如果你下载STL, 纹理信息不会随之而来。
Yeah, but if you download STL, the texture information will not come with it.
摆 没事 故无碍.
Okay. Yeah, it's okay. So it doesn't matter.
没有
No.
摆 谢谢 我可以试试
Okay. Thank you. I can try it.
对
Yeah.
摆
Okay.
这么说
So
我们能重新开始吗?
shall we start again?
然后我们会得到
Then we will get
回来... 现在我们去Blender,因为
back... Now we will go to Blender, because
如果你有一个模型,那么我们会看看我们如何
if you have a model, then we will see how we can
准备和进一步修改
prepare it and further modify it for
编造。 这里有Blender屏幕。
fabrication. So here we have the Blender screen.
我先来
I will first
导入一个模型。
import one model.
我一开始说,进口型号是一个单位 它在米,
As I started with saying, the import model is one unit and it's in meters,
所以,当我们把它送到切片机时,它就会产生效果
so it will have an effect when we send it to the slicer
用于激光切割。 但是,现在,我将保持原样。
for laser cutting. But for now, I will leave it as it is.
还有
And
然后我们的人就在这里
then we have our person in the center here.
我们需要两个加注才能准备
We need to have two add-ons to be able to prepare
这个
this
模式
model for
编造。
fabrication.
为了能够做到这一点,我们需要能够增加它们,如果我们没有它们的话。
To be able to do that, we need to be able to add them, if we don't have them.
我们需要去优惠。 我在用麦克
We need to go to Preferences. I'm using a Mac.
我不知道,如果
I don't know if
菜单位置对Mac或Windows不同,
places of the menus are different for Mac or Windows,
但我只有麦克 如果你已经使用它们, 如果你已经下载
but I have Mac only. And if you have used them, if you have downloaded the
扩展名之前,您可以到 Add-ons 并选择它们 。
extensions before, you can go to Add-ons and select them.
但如果你以前没吃过,就去享受优惠
But if you haven't had them before, go to Get Extensions under Preferences and
安装这两个
install these two
扩展,加载. 你可以找到他们
extensions, add-ons. You can find them by
寻找这里。 一是三维印等.
searching here. One is 3D Print, blah, blah, blah.
如果搜索,可以安装.
If you search it, you can install it.
自从我有了它, 它不显示安装盒在这里, 安装按钮在这里,但
Since I have it, it doesn't show the install box here, install button here, but
您需要通过点击它来安装, 或者,还有布尔工具,
you need to install it by clicking on it or, and also the Bool Tool,
它可以让我们在物体上进行布尔操作。
which will allow us to make boolean operations on the object.
第三个会确保我们有多重几何,这意味着
And the third one will make sure that we have manifold geometry, which means a
紧水几何
watertight geometry for-
对不起
Sorry.
对
Yep.
我们看不到你的喜好屏幕
We can't see your preferences screen there.
是吗? 哦,谢谢你...
You don't? Oh, thank you for-
没有
No.
摆 然后,我将分享我的全屏。
Okay. Then I will share my full screen.
摆 对 谢谢你告诉我
Okay. Yeah. Thank you for letting me know.
就像我说的,这是
As I said, it's
当你看不到别人所看到的时 很难过 我会分享我的整个屏幕。
really hard when you don't see what others see. I will share my entire screen.
忍我一会。 现在我们在正确的屏幕上。
Bear with me for a second. Now we are in the right screen.
因此,我们将去优惠。 现在你看到我的喜好屏幕了吗?
So we will go to Preferences. Now do you see my preferences screen?
对
Yeah.
好吧,冷静。 你去"获得扩展",
Okay, cool. You go to Get Extensions,
在“获取扩展”下,您可以输入扩展的名称
and then under Get Extensions, you can type the name of the extensions that you
想要,我们想要的扩展为3D打印工具箱和布尔工具。
want, and the extensions that we want are 3D Print Toolbox and Bool Tool.
所以如果你开始在这里打字,Boul工具,
So if you start typing here, Bool Tool,
它们将出现在可用的扩展名下,您需要
they will appear under the available extensions, and you need to
点击 Boul 工具旁边的安装按钮安装它们,
install them by clicking the install button next to Bool Tool,
然后在安装的区域出现
and then they will appear on the installed area
,或者移动到已安装的区域,对于3D打印工具箱,您也需要这样做。
or move to the installed area, and you need to do the same for 3D Print Toolbox.
安装后,你可以去
And after they are installed, you can go to
添加和确保它们被点击,这意味着它们作为
Add-ons and make sure that they are clicked, which means that they are available as
Blender内部的加载。
an add-on inside Blender.
接下来
Then,
我们有我们的人在这里。 自从我们创造了这个人
we have our human here. Since we generated this guy
或这个人,
or this person,
你看,它没有 平底,我也许也想...
you see that it does not have a flat base, and I might also want to...
但我想要一个平坦的基座 这样它会保持一点点
But I would like a flat base so that it stays a little bit
我把它放在桌子上,然后我编造出来。
vertical and I put it on the table after I fabricate it.
所以,我想在那里建立一个切。 我该怎么做?
So I would like to create a cut there. How do I do it?
我……
I
添加网状平面。 之前,我加,也许你可以移动
add a mesh plane. Before I add it, maybe you can move the
光标到您想要制造平面的位置,
cursor to a location that you want to make a plane,
和
and
也可以在此之后更改此位置。 但现在,我会把它放在这里。
you can also change this location afterwards. But for now, I will put it here.
实际所在. 增加梅什和梅什飞机.
It's actually where it is. Add Mesh and Plane Mesh.
我生成后,
And after I generate it,
你看,它有点低, 所以我需要移动它一点点上,以便
you see that it is a little bit below, so I need to move it a little bit up so that
它穿过我的目标 这些是这里的修饰工具,所以你可以移动,
it cuts through my object. These are the modifier tools here, so you can move,
旋转, 缩放
rotate, scale
任何几何学 我们移动它一点点,这样
any kind of geometry you have. And we move it a little bit up so that
我知道那伤了我的身体
I know that cuts through my object.
等我搞定这个... 现在这是一架飞机。
And after I'm done with this... Now this is a plane.
因此,一个平面几何是不坚实的,
So a plane geometry is not solid,
这意味着我不能用它做布尔操作, 所以我不能减去
which means that I cannot do boolean operations with it, so that I cannot subtract
或者切开我的模型
or slice my model
与这架飞机。 所以我得把这做成一个坚固的物体 就像我的飞机一样
with this plane. So I need to make this a solid object, like my plane, like my
模型,人类模型。 所以在这右边
model, human model. So here on the right-hand side,
你会的
you will
添加...
add...
对不起
Sorry.
添加修饰器、生成器和团结。
Add Modifier, Generate, and Solidify.
所以当我加上这个,
So when I add this,
你会看到
you will see that
没错
it is
有点厚了
a little bit thicker now.
礛
And then
我会打
I will hit
应用在这个下。 现在我有了这个东西。
Apply under this. So now I have this object.
摆
Okay.
所以,这个部分,我知道 这可能会有点太复杂,
So this part, I know this could be a little bit too complicated,
复杂,但这部分,我还附上了YouTube教程
intricate, but this part, I also attached a YouTube tutorial
在米罗板。 所以,如果你不能跟着现在, 你也可以这样做
in the Miro board. So if you cannot follow along right now, you can also do it
之后,在这个讲习班之后。
afterwards, after this workshop.
我们现在有这个人 和这个固化的飞机, 这是一个3D
So we have this guy now and this solidified plane, which is a 3D
而我们就要把这家伙分开
box at the moment, and we are going to split this guy
用这架飞机,让我们有一个平坦的基地。
with this plane so that we have a flat base.
我们要点击他 然后再加一个修饰符
We are going to click on the guy and then add another modifier.
因为我们加入了布尔工具 现在我们可以添加布尔
Because we added the boolean Bool Tool, now we are able to add a boolean
操作器, 修改器
operator on it, modifier
所以我们加入了布尔修饰剂。 汝见差别.
So we add the Boolean modifier. You see the difference.
将取其异.
We're going to take the difference of it.
这么说
So
然后操作器是我的对象,它被选中,
and then the operant is my object, which is selected, and
现在我要点击滴眼器工具 选择这个
then now I'm going to click on the eyedropper tool and select this
飞机
plane.
然后,你看到飞机变成了现在的物体。
And then you see the plane becomes the object now.
一旦我完成了,
And once I'm done,
我会应用这个。
I will apply this.
看来什么都没发生
So it appears like nothing has happened
因为我们还有这架飞机
because we still have this plane here.
但如果我删除这个平面,你可以删除 Blender 中的对象,如果你选择
But if I delete this plane, and you can delete objects in Blender, if you select
在键盘上按下 X, 弹出就会打开。
the object and hit X on your keyboard, you will have this pop-up open.
删除选中的对象 。 删除,现在删除.
Delete selected objects. Delete it, and it's deleted now.
所以,你可以看到,现在上下之间有分歧。
So you see there is a split now between the top and the bottom.
但当我选择物体时,它们仍然在一起。
But when I select the object, they are still together.
因此,为了能够分开他们,分开他们,
So to be able to separate them, split them,
选择对象后,我会去编辑模式。
after selecting my object, I will go to edit mode.
你会看到这里发生了什么
You'll see something is happening here.
当我
When I
按我键盘上的A
press A on my keyboard,
所有的东西
everything
中选择对象。 如果我打中了P的话 And if I hit P,
within the object is selected. And if I hit P,
然后,它将被分成若干部分,
then it will separate by loose parts,
也就是说它会把两部分分开
which means that it will separate the two parts
对象。
of the object.
现在你看到他们分开了
Now you see that they are separated.
我可以离开物体模式。 现在我有两个不同的物体。
And I can leave the object mode. Now I have two different objects.
一个是这个,另一个是这个。 我不需要这个部分,所以我可以删除它
One is this and the other is this. And I don't need this part, so I can delete it
键盘上按 X 并删除。
by pressing X on my keyboard and deleting.
现在,我的物体有一个平底。 你也可以这样
And now my object has a flat base. You can also do these kind of
变量,如果您想要删除手臂。
variations if you want to delete the arms.
正如我所说,如果你想删除模型的某些部分,那就不容易了
As I said, if you want to delete some parts of the model, it's not easy to do it
通过要求 AI 图像生成从
by asking AI image generation to cut it exactly from
随便你 但你可以在这里做到这一点, 你不需要跟着这个
where you want. But you can do it here by, you don't need to follow along with this
一,通过加网,然后
one, by adding a mesh and then
移到这里一点点,
moving it up here a little bit,
我们再放大一点
and let's scale it a little bit,
更进一步,
scale it further,
搬过来
and move it here.
对不起 然后旋转它,
Oops, sorry. And then rotate it,
我轻轻移动它。
and I move it slightly.
所以,如果我想把它切到这里, 我将无法做到这一点。
So if I wanted it cut exactly here, I would not be able to do it in
AI 生成模式,但
AI generation mode, but
我办得到
I can do it
这里在Blender。 或者,我也可以做到这一点之前,我的形象发送到
here in Blender. Or, I could also do it before sending my image to
Gemini或另一个LM.
Gemini or another LLM.
在这里,我们同样需要这样做。 我将增加一个修饰语。
Here again, we need to do the same thing. I will add a modifier.
哎哟
Oops.
结实一点厚度,这是很好的, 然后我应用它。
Solidify a little bit of thickness, which is nice, and then I apply it.
我现在有了,然后我再补充
I have it now, and then I will add
a 这里的布尔, 差数, 选择此平面对象,
a Boolean here, difference, select this plane object,
应用。 现在再说一次,我有这个
apply. Now again, I have this
分离。
separated.
我可以去这个,
I can go to this,
选择此对象, 在编辑模式下打开, 按下全部选择
select this object, open it in edit mode, select all by pressing
我键盘上的
A on my keyboard.
我按键盘上按P就可以分开 松开就可以分开
I can separate them by pressing P on my keyboard and separate it by loose
组件。 你会看到这已经分开了
parts. You'll see that this is separated now.
然后我可以退出对象编辑模式,然后
And then I can exit the object edit mode, and then
删除此松散部分。 对 所以,一旦我完成了,我有一个模型。
delete this loose part. Yeah. So once I'm done, I have this model.
现在我要查一下我能不能打印出3D还是多维
Now I need to check if I can 3D print it, or if it's a manifold
物体或紧水物体。 这么说
object or a watertight object. So
您可以打开此三维打印标签
you can open this 3D print tab
请点击这里。
by clicking here.
你看到了吗? 有时你看不到,但如果你点击这边,你可以
Do you see it? Sometimes you don't see it, but if you click on this side, you can
看见了 然后我要选择我的目标 然后
see it. And then I am going to select my object and then
说,"做多。" 你会看到它修改了一些顶点,
say, "Make manifold." You'll see that it modified a few vertices,
几边,表面使它变得多。
a few edges, and surfaces to make it manifold.
你需要按多键
And you need to press manifold
作为
as
您达到零顶点,零边缘,零面。
you reach zero vertices, zero edges, and zero faces.
那就意味着你的模特儿
Then it means that your model is
关闭。
closed.
对不起,多面和紧水一样吗?
Sorry, manifold and watertight is the same?
对
Yeah.
摆 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
对不起,如果我们没有 3D打印选项在侧面,
Sorry, if we don't have this 3D print option on the side,
我们在哪里能找到
where can we find
做出多重选择?
make manifold option?
如果这里没有3D打印, 你找不到它 。
You cannot find it if you don't have the 3D print here.
是的,我没有,所以如何添加它?
Yeah, I don't have, so how to add it?
你需要去喜欢。
You need to go to preferences.
对
Mm-hmm.
您是否添加了 3D 打印扩展名 ?
Did you add the 3D print extension?
我下载了Blender 我和Rico一起编辑
I downloaded Blender, and I edit with Rico
MakeHuman类延伸,但除此之外,没有。
Make Human extension, but apart from that, no.
好吧,所以去得到扩展 并添加3D打印
Okay, so go to get extensions and add 3D print
工具箱 工具箱 工具箱
toolbox.
我想作一点澄清。
I would like to make a small clarification.
水紧是当没有洞, 这意味着如果你
Watertight is when there are no holes, meaning that if you
将物体淹没在水瓶中 里面没有水
submerge the object in a bottle of water, no water goes inside,
意思是关门了
meaning that it's closed.
曼尼佛和非曼尼佛不一定就是那样。
Manifold and non-manifold is not necessarily exactly that.
这也意味着没有面孔不附着。
It also means that there are no faces that they are not attached.
例如,你做了一些东西, 突然一个三角形进入你的满
For example, you made something, and suddenly a triangle was going inside your full
对象,它完全不附加。
object, and it is not attaching at all.
没有边缘是开放的, 内部墙壁,它是
There are no edges that they're open, internal walls, and it's
有点不同 不过...
a little bit different. But just-
对
Yeah.
如果你进入这个过程,你的模型中没有自我交互的部分.
If you go into that, there are no self-intersecting parts in your model.
没错
Exactly.
对 我不想让它一点点...
Yeah. I don't want to make it a little bit-
对
Yeah
更复杂 这就是为什么,为了这个, 我说他们是
... more complicated. That's why for the sake of this, I said that they are the
一样,但他们不是。 所以应该没有开口和自我交流
same, but they are not. So there should be no openings and no self-intersecting
能够称之为多重几何的部件, 但水紧是当它是
parts to be able to call it a manifold geometry, but watertight is only when it is
关闭对象。
a closed object.
对
Yes.
这么说
So,
我不知道是谁问的
I don't know who asked the question,
但你能找到那个...
but were you able to find the-
没有 也许我需要先下载 然后...
No. Probably I need to first download, and then-
是啊,你可以做到这一点非常快。 受优待,受优待
Yeah, you can do it very quickly. It's under preferences, under get
扩展。 你看到我的屏幕了吗?
extensions. Do you see my screen now?
我看得出来 不过...
I can see. However-
对
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
您在此输入三维打印工具箱, 您看到的名称, 然后单击
So you type here 3D print toolbox, the name that you see here, and then click
安装,然后出现。
install, and then it will appear.
对 我无法找到它。 我搜过3D
Yes. I cannot find it. I searched 3D.
对,我找不到
Yeah, I cannot find it.
你写过指纹吗? 也许这会有所帮助。
Did you write print? Maybe that will help.
印报. 我写了3D 哦,是的,你说得对。 好吧,完美无缺。
Print. I wrote 3D. Oh, yes, you are right. Okay, perfect.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
不用谢
You're welcome.
是的,湿婆
Yes, Shivam
对 顿
Yes. Hi.
顿
Hi
我有一些非疯狂的边缘 和交叉面孔。
I have some non-manifold edges and intersecting faces.
对
Mm-hmm.
我们如何解决这个问题? 还是下一个部分?
How do we solve that? Or is that the next part?
你说什么?
Sorry?
我们如何解决这些问题? 我有19个非疯狂的边缘和11个交叉
How do we resolve those issues? I have 19 non-manifold edges and 11 intersecting
脸
faces.
在3D打印中点击“ Make Manifold”。
So you click on the Make Manifold on the Cleanup in 3D Print.
所以你需要到这个3D打印标签...
So you need to go to this 3D Print tab-
对
Mm-hmm
去打扫一下
... and go to Cleanup.
对 是的,我这样做。
Yeah. Yeah, I did that.
礛...
And then... Mm-hmm.
然后它说,
And then it said,
在底部,加上零顶点,加上零边缘,加上零面.
at the bottom, plus zero vertices, plus zero edges, plus zero faces.
摆 那就没事了
Okay. Then it's fine now.
摆
Okay.
对
Yeah.
所以,也许这就是我的3D模型的性质,也许? 这就是原因吗?
So maybe that is the nature of my 3D model, maybe? Is that the reason?
我不知道,但我也有这个。 当我检查所有, 我也有一些问题。
I don't know, but I also had that. When I Check All, I also had some problems.
上面写着"非狂人" 但我后来把它导入了切片软件
It said non-manifold, but I was able to import it to a slicer software afterwards
当我...
when I-
还好
Okay
. . . . 因此,希望它将解决问题。
... did the Make Manifold. So hopefully it will resolve the issues.
伐 摆
Okay, awesome. Okay.
摆 还有问题吗?
Okay. Any more questions?
要我继续吗?
Shall I continue?
如果我们觉得这太大了 我们可以做点别的
And something else that we can do, if we think that this is too big of a
多计数器,我们也可以去 添加修饰器和去十进制,它会
poly count, we can also go Add Modifier and go to Decimate, which will
减少我们的综合数。 所以,你看我们现在有了
decrease our poly count. So you see we have now
94 000人
94,000
脸数,但我们可以减少
face count, but we can decrease it
如果我们想减少它。 很明显
if we want to decrease it. So it will obviously
降低我们模式的分辨率,
decrease the resolution of our model,
但与此同时,使它对切片软件更轻.
but at the same time, make it lighter for slicing software.
因此,我们需要去 这个下箭头,点击应用,
So again, we need to go to this down arrow, click Apply,
应该就是这样 然后我们再来一次 然后我们就可以走了
and that should be it. And then let's do another manifold again, and then we can go
通过选择对象,可以导出为 STL。
to, by selecting the object, we can export it as STL.
对不起 你从哪里找到Decimate的?
Sorry. Where did you find Decimate?
这里。 选择对象,然后在此属性下,
Here. Select the object, and then here under the Properties,
添加修饰器、生成器和解析器。
Add Modifier, Generate, and Decimate.
谢谢
Thank you.
你需要选择人类人物 这样修改...
You need to have the human figure selected so that the modify-
对
Yeah.
你能再展示一次吗? 对不起。
Can you show it again? Excuse me.
摆
Okay.
对
Yeah.
所以,如果你没有 modif - 哦,现在我有了,但是
So if you do not have the modif- Oh, now I have it, but
选择对象,您的人形,然后去添加修饰器,
select the object, your human figure, and then go to Add Modifier,
产生,和deimate。
Generate, and Decimate.
哦,我们没有看到它现在。
Oh, we don't see it now.
你没看见吗?
You don't see it?
单单 对,等一下 对
Ah, wait, wait. Yeah, wait a second. Yeah.
摆
Okay.
对 我的脸 我的脸
Yeah. Under Decimate, now because I already done this, my face
计数是67000。
count is at 67,000.
但如果我想,我可以,再次,改变这一点。
But if I want, I can, again, change this.
摆 现在,
Okay. Now,
我们会把它导出。
we will export this.
选择对象,然后导出,
Select the object, and then Export,
然后选择一个位置,然后写出您的名称
and then you choose a location, and then write the name of your
型号,
model,
讲习班
Workshop
人类
Human.
阿斯利,对不起。 你能再次显示导出按钮吗 ? 对
Asli, I'm sorry. Can you show the Export button again? Yep.
所以,我们在哪里 在3D打印 -嗯...
So where we were under 3D Print- Mm-hmm ...
我们有清扫...
we had the Cleanup- Oh, okay ... Make Manifold, and then we have the Export.
对 所以,你需要点击这个,然后它会打开它。 摆 谢谢
Mm-hmm. So you need to click this, and then it will open it up. Okay. Thank you.
对 然后你会出口它。
Mm-hmm. And then you will export it.
还有...
And there-
抱歉打扰了 我回来了
Sorry to interrupt, I'm a bit back.
对
Yes.
我安装了3D打印扩展,但我看不到3D
I installed the 3D Print extension, but I don't see that 3D
打印
Print
那种事情 你身边,那个。 摆
kind of thing on the side that you have, that one. Okay.
所以有时候你看不到这些 但有一个小标签
So sometimes it happens that you don't see these here, but there is a small tab
你可以看见。 如果您点击此标签, 它会立即打开 。
that you can see. If you click this tab, it will open up right away.
对 对 它就在这里。
Oh, right. Yeah. It's in there.
怎么样?
Good?
对
Yes.
Yeah.
对不起,所以我需要在这里的场景?
And sorry, so the setting that I need to have here?
您选择您的对象, 而这个...
You select your object, and this-
对
Yes
...这应该像这样关闭。
... this should be closed like this.
当它先打开时,点击下面的下拉菜单,放在清理旁边.
When you have it open first, you click on the dropdown menu under, next to Cleanup.
清理,是的。
Cleanup, yeah.
然后造曼i罗.
And then Make Manifold.
摆 就那样?
Okay. Just that?
对
Yeah.
摆
Okay.
然后确认... 你需要做几次,直到你看到没有
And then make sure... You need to do it maybe several times until you see no
圆顶,
vertices,
和
and
边缘和面部位于底部,你看有多少被修改,直到你
edges and faces are at the bottom, you see how many are modified, until you
见千.
see 000.
对不起,在哪里? 你能带我去我该看哪吗?
Sorry, where? Can you show me where I should see 000?
所以当你... 它只是消失得很快。
So when you... It just disappears very quickly.
做,对。 曼尼佛尔.
Make, yeah. Manifold.
但是,当你点击Make Manifold, 它应该出现在屏幕下面...
But when you click Make Manifold, it should appear under the screen here-
对
Yeah
...有情报
... with an information.
哦,没关系。
Oh, okay.
对
Yeah.
摆
Okay.
然后我们...
And then we do-
好吧,所有零号。 还好
Okay, all zero. Okay
...导出。
... Export.
我看到很多事情都发生在
I see that there has been a lot happening in the
闲聊吧
chat.
对
Oh, yeah.
对 我只是读 通过聊天。
Mm-hmm. I'm just reading through the chat.
摆 我想现在一切都得到了答案。
Okay. I think all are answered now.
我们可以继续前进。 现在我们有我们的模型STL下载。
We can move on. Now we have our model STL downloaded.
显然,我需要先选择它,然后
Obviously, I need to first select it, and then
台词
Desktop.
人类讲习班,
Workshop Human,
并导出。
and Export.
摆 现在我回去
Okay. Now I will go back to
米罗板再次告诉你我们在哪里
the Miro board again to show you where we are in the process.
如你所见,我们已经完成了二维图像生成,图像到三维
As you see, we have done the 2D image generation, image to 3D
生成、三维模型的修改和生产验证,以及
generation, 3D model modification and verification for fabrication, and now in the
制造准备过程。
fabrication preparation process.
哎哟
Oops.
对不起
Sorry.
现在我们可以用切片机做
And now we can either do it with the slicer that
Anastasia在工作室开始时出现, 但我在想,我开始
Anastasia showed at the beginning of the workshop, but I was thinking, I started
可能几个月前,因为斯利切
thinking about this maybe a few months ago, that how, because Slicer
因为Fusion 已停止, 它现在可以给错误, 或者它可以
for Fusion is discontinued and it can give bugs now, or it can
关机,现在不可靠了,我们怎么可以
shut down, and it's not very reliable now, how can we
做我们自己的版本吗? 或者我们如何使用AI 来生成我们的
make our own version of it? Or how can we use AI to be able to generate our
拥有制造工具吗?
own fabrication tools with it?
我在这里
And here I
首先问ChatGPT:"你能切一个3D模型吗?
first asked ChatGPT, "Can you slice a 3D model
用于激光切割的STL 给我XL文件?" DXF文件,对不起。
STL for laser cutting and give me the XL file?" The DXF file, sorry.
DXF是一个
DXF is a
可互换的文件格式
file format that is an interchangeable
2D 向量使用的自动桌面文件格式
Autodesk file format that is used for 2D vectors that
非常可靠,或者你也可以使用 SVG,当然, 但我发现DXF更多
is very reliable, or you can use also SVG, of course, but I find DXF more
可靠性。 ChatGPT说,"是的,我可以做到这一点,但你需要
reliable. And ChatGPT says, "Yes, I can do that, but you need to
选择这个和这个,或者选择这个和这个和那个". 然后当我看着
select this and this, or choose this and this and that." And then when I looked at
我说,“我们也许可以和他们一起工作,但后来我想
the possibilities, I said, "We can maybe work with those, but then I think an
界面可以选择这些更理想,如用于
interface to be able to choose those would be more ideal, like a Slicer for
融合"。 所以我说我想制作一个小型的网络应用软件 来做这个,并把它想象出来
Fusion." So I said I want to create a small web app to do that and visualize it
而不是通过这里选择 或写作或与这样的模型交谈
rather than selecting it through here or writing or talking to a model like this
在这里。
here.
这么说
So
我开始制作一个小网络应用 与Loveable。
I started making a small web app with Lovable.
如果你不了解Loveable,Loveable, 它允许你创造快速
If you don't know Lovable, Lovable, it allows you to create quick
网站再次使用
websites using, again,
语言
language
喜欢英语。
like English.
你不需要知道编码。 您可以使用语义语言生成模型,
You don't need to know coding. You can use semantic languages to generate models,
对不起,网站。 还有
sorry, websites. And
我们开始做一个快速的网络原型, 但有很多
we started making a rapid first web prototype, but there were a lot of
有问题 第一次也不错
problems with it. And also it was a good first
快速原型,但也没有 大部分的功能 我想要它。
quick prototype, but also did not have most of the functions that I wanted it.
是啊,很多的虫子在总体上。 然后我想继续工作
And yeah, a lot of bugs in general. And then I wanted to continue working with
喜欢,但后来我很快就用光了免费的信贷, 我不想付钱
Lovable, but then I ran out of free credits very quickly, and I did not want to pay
很明显,我更想控制它
for it, obviously, and I want to be able to be more in control of it,
并使其成为开源。 所以我说,"让我们搬到GitHub。" 所以,我们有
and also make it open source. So I said, "Let's move to GitHub." So that we have
这个第一个接口,
this first interface,
在 GitHub 上托管的网站的代码, 代码所在
the code of the website hosted on GitHub where the code is
存储,我们可以跟踪变化。
stored, and we can track the changes.
我也做了一个本地的
And I also made a local
存储器或复制器, 这样我就可以调试和查看
repository or a clone of it so that I can debug and see
易变.
transformations easily.
很明显,我不是编解码师,我不是工程师,所以我无法做到这一点
Obviously, I'm not a coder, I'm not an engineer, so I would not be able to do this
没有ChatGPT,但我一直在编织
without ChatGPT, but I have been fabricating and
在电脑上设计了这么久,我才能输入我的东西
designing on computers for so long that I can be able to give the input of what I
想要,我想要它, 什么样的特征 这东西需要,或者我可以
want, how I want it, what kind of features this thing needs, or I can
必要时也调试它。 我们需要做很多调试。
also debug it when necessary. And we needed to do a lot of debugging.
因此从这个第一个模型
So from this first model
最后一张,你先看
to the final one, so you see that first
我不得不调查
I had to look into
上传不同的几何图形. 故以花瓶为始.
uploading different geometries. So it starts with a vase.
比较容易
It's easier to
切开 你看这里的轮廓。 它会切片。
slice it. You see the contours here. It slices.
每片一个物体,没问题.
It's one object per slice, and it's not a problem.
它不给你 制造顺序或数量 零件,这是非常
It doesn't give you the fabrication order or number of the parts, which is very
对制造很重要 因为想象一下你拥有真正
important for fabrication, because imagine that you have objects that are really
大小类似。 如果你不知道的话
similar in size. If you don't know the
部件编号, 您不能将它们组合在一起 。
parts number, you cannot put them together.
于是我们开始调查,我加入了,但后来
So we started looking into that, and I added that, but then
带有多个部件的切片没有生成部件
slices with multiple parts did not generate part
数字在另一边。 所以我们调查了一下。 所以很多调试。
numbers on the other side. So we looked into that. So a lot of debugging.
然后,筑巢是另一个问题, 再次, 多个部分在一个切片。
And then the nesting was another problem, again, with multiple parts on one slice.
你怎么解决这个? 然后调查华夫饼结构
How do you solve this? And then looking into waffle structures,
这是Anastasi在开头也表现出来的另一个可能性
that's another possibility that Anastasi also showed in the beginning with the
切片器 也可以做华夫饼片。
slicer profusion that you can also do waffle slices.
最初,它没有产生 我想要的切片 或切的部分
Initially, it did not generate the slices that I want or the cuts where the parts
可以一起溜进去。
can slip together.
所以很多调试,测试,
So a lot of debugging, testing,
以及标签、对齐和不同选项。
and labeling and alignments and different options.
礛
Then
我终于想出了一个工作版本 尽管我的工作
I was able to come up with a working version now, although the functions that I
渴望未来不再存在。 现在可以了
want for the future are not there. It is usable now.
好吧,GitHub版本是不错的,但并非人人都能访问.
And okay, the GitHub version is nice, but it's not accessible for everyone.
所以有一个Vercel的应用, 所以它允许我发布它现场,
So there is a Vercel app, so it allows me to publish it live, and
这是应用程序
this is the app
我在ChatGPT的帮助下创造的,
that I sort of created with the help of ChatGPT,
我将分享这个链接。
and I will share the link.
但你没有用探员?
But you didn't use agents?
没有
No.
你用过聊天吗?
You used the chat?
我用了聊天, 因为我想能够控制什么
I used the chat, and because I wanted to be able to be in control of what's
整个过程
happening all along the
一步一步的,因为我试图,例如,一夜之间
step-by-step because when I tried to, for example, do overnight
处决,但我不知道发生了什么。
executions, but then I did not know what was happening.
所以我无法控制所发生的一切。
So I was not in control of what was happening.
有时我甚至不允许它进入我的GitHub仓库。
Sometimes I even did not allow it to access my GitHub repository.
我问在哪里我需要修改代码, 我去了我的地方仓库和
I asked where I needed to change in the code, and I went to my local repository and
我自己做改变,然后把它推到我的 Git 仓库,以便能够知道
make the changes myself and then push it to my Git repository to be able to know
程序里到底发生了什么
exactly what was going on in the app.
所以,是的,我要写这个。 我的谈话呢?
So yeah, I was going to write this. Where is my chat?
这是...
Here is the...
对
Yes.
我刚看到一个问题。 此应用程序的核心功能是您有 3D
I just saw a question. The core function of this app is you have a 3D
模型,但如果你想用
model, but if you want to create it with
一台CNC机器,就像用木头, 我没有木头的功能,但是
a CNC machine, like with chopwood, I don't have the chopwood functionalities, but
磨削或激光切割, 你需要将其切成若干个间隔,通常是
milling or laser cutting, you need to slice it in several intervals, usually the
材料的厚度,这样你就可以
thickness of the material, so that you can
将这些切片交给激光切割器,然后创建
give these slices to the laser cutter and then create the
与它们同在的物质, 与它们的切片, 与它们的零件, 然后把它们放在
material objects with them, slices with them, parts with them, and then put them on
互相顶上,互相粘上
top of each other, glue them on top of each other
体质上
physically to have
一个真正的物体。
a real object.
这就是功能。 清楚了吗 还是你想我...
So that is the function. Was it clear or do you want me to...
因此,例如,对于一个这样的对象的文件, 它生成切片,
So, for example, for a file for an object like this, it generates the slices,
你有这些切片。 当你输出时,
and you have these slices. When you export them,
它会给您一个您需要的 DXF 工作表或所有工作表的文件
it gives you the file that you need to sheet DXF or all sheets
一起来
together.
它给你的文件,你需要拿 到激光切割器,以便你可以
It gives you the files that you need to take to the laser cutter so that you can
用它来剪激光
use this for laser cutting.
明白了吗?
Is that clear?
对
Yes.
没错
Yes, exactly.
是的,擦擦编码,我喜欢它, 但正如我所说, 这是非常重要的。
Yeah, wipe coding, I like it, but as I said, it is very important.
你不能这样做, 这就是我想要回来。
You cannot do that, and that is what I wanted to come back to.
作为一个人类,你需要确定需要。 您需要指定特性 。
As a human, you need to identify the need. You need to specify the features.
你需要对照真实的捏造来评估结果和测试执行情况
You need to evaluate the results and test implementations against real fabrication
要求并不断纠正技术和可用性问题。
requirements and keep correcting technical and usability problems.
所以这很重要。 如果你没有专家知识,领域
So that is really important. If you don't have the expert knowledge, domain
知识 经验 基本上不能抹去代码
knowledge, experience with it, you cannot wipe code, basically.
所以,实际上人工智能的工作, 我们做清洁。
So actually the AI does the job, and we do the cleaning.
没有 我是说...
No. I mean,
一点点,但你需要具体说明AI需要做什么。
a little bit, but you need to specify what AI needs to do.
它不会自动产生华夫饼板,即使它制造华夫饼
It does not automatically create waffle slabs, or even if it creates waffle
正如我向你们展示的那样,
structures, as I showed you,
首页
the initial
操作是这个,然后你需要说, 好吧,所有的切片需要
operant is this, and then you need to say that, okay, all the slits need to
来到每一节的中间。
come to the middle of each section.
所以,你需要操作这些, 你需要说它们需要交叉
So you need to operate those, and you need to say that they need to be intersected
与边界对象并修剪。
with the boundary object and trimmed.
因此,为了能够说出这些事情, 你需要有域知识。
So to be able to say these kind of things, you need to have the domain knowledge.
因此,例如,从这个到
And so, for example, from this to
这之后。 要能够到达那里,你看,
this afterwards. To be able to get there, you see,
你得知道发生了什么
you need to be able to tell what is going on.
在这里,你可以看到,我也有 每一个作品叫做
And here you see that I have also each piece is called
写在切片上,这样你也可以把它们重新组合起来,组装起来
Written on the slits so that you can also put them back together, assemble them
在一起,而你没有他们在这里。
together, whereas you don't have them here.
并且为了能说出事情的真相, 它不是一个仅仅产生魔法的工具
And to be able to say what's going on, it's not a magic tool that just generates
东西。
things.
FormSlice 基本工作类似于
FormSlice basically works similar to
用于融合的刀片,但较少
Slicer for Fusion, but with less
现在。
features now.
但是如果你来到这里,让我们
But if you come here, let's
打开
open
从头开始 这样您就可以上传STL, 或者您也可以下降
it from scratch. So you can upload an STL, or you can also drop
这里有一个STL文件。 所以,让我们把最后一个
an STL file here. So let's put our last
我们掉在这里的人
human that we dropped here,
还有...
and then-
阿斯利,你需要分享你的屏幕吗?
Asli, do you need to share your screen?
你说什么?
Sorry?
您需要分享您的屏幕还是...
Do you need to share your screen or-
我的屏幕现在不共享吗?
Is my screen not shared at the moment?
没有
No.
这是共同的。 我看见...
It is shared. I see the-
是的,我看得出来
Yeah, I can see
……FormSlice。
... FormSlice.
摆 是吗?
Okay. Hmm.
你看到其他人在Zoom上吗? 有时候我会这么做
Do you see other people on Zoom? Sometimes I do that.
路易莎 如果是这样的话
Luiza, if that is the case-
我见众生.
I'm seeing people.
摆 如果是这样,去你的缩放屏幕的顶端
Okay. If that is the case, go to the upper edge of your Zoom screen and there's
那边有个标签 一个说见面。
a tab there. One says Meeting.
摆 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
我做了几次,没问题。
I did that a few times, no problem.
对 摆 所以,你放下你的人, 然后选择大小。
Yeah. Okay. So you drop your human, and then you choose the size.
就像我说的,它来
As I said, it comes with
1毫米,几乎1毫米。
one millimeter, almost one millimeter.
因此,我们显然需要扩大规模。
So we need to obviously increase the size.
还有
And
你也可以随意旋转
then you can also rotate it however you like,
然后重设它。 那个家伙去哪了? 显然,这个也不见了。
and then reset it. Well, where did the guy go? Obviously, this is also gone.
贡举二百名.
Let's make it 200.
还有
And
您可以在此选择, 如果您想要堆叠的切片, 这意味着它们将会是
you can choose here if you want stacked slices, which means that they will be
堆放在一个方向,或者你可以有华夫饼,这意味着它会有一个
stacked in one direction, or you can have waffle, which means that it will have a
华夫饼结构.
waffle structure.
希望接下来是放射片 我还没拿到
Radial slices hopefully will come next. I don't have them yet.
所以如果你选择堆叠的切片,
So if you choose stacked slices,
您可以通过厚度或计数来选择。
you can choose by thickness or by count.
所以,如果你选择厚度,你可以思考 物质厚度,你有多少
So if you choose thickness, you can think about material thickness, how much you
想要吗? 您也可以在切片之间有空间。
want. You can also have space in between the slices.
你可以改变偏移。 有时候你需要做一点
You can change the offset. Sometimes you need to do this by a little bit
因为如果有一点
because if there is a point
如果模型结束,则无法用切片计算。
where the model ends, it cannot calculate with a slice.
我的意思是,它不能与切片相交, 所以你可能需要稍微移动它
I mean, it cannot intersect with a slice, so you might need to move it slightly
向下或向上移动。 您也可以更改顺序, 然后曲线
down or up. You can also change the order, and then curve
补偿,你可以让它保持原样。
compensation, you can leave it as it is.
曲线是被激光吃掉的物质 因为激光
Curve is the material eaten away by the laser, because laser
减少
cuts by
烧了材料。 因此,通过燃烧,
burning the material. So by that burning,
一定量的材料被吃掉,所以是为了反驳这一点.
a certain amount of the material is eaten away, so it's to counter that.
曲线模式是自动的,这意味着它位于外侧和孔,然后
Curve mode is auto, which means that it's on the outer side and the holes, and then
这是伪造的 所以正如我所说,你需要能够标注
this is for fabrication. So as I said, you need to be able to label
每一部分,以便你随后组装它们。
each part so that you can assemble them afterwards.
然后您也可以指定它们有多高,有多大。
And then you can also specify how high, how big you want them to be.
对于双孔,
So for double holes,
你必须...
you need to...
有时候,当你把切片堆在一起, 与华夫饼,你没有
Sometimes when you stack slices on top of each other, with waffles, you don't have
问题就在于他们这样聚在一起
that problem because they come together like this.
但用堆叠的切片,它们可以移动一点点,所以你需要一个内
But with stacked slices, they can shift a little bit, so you need an inner
结构,和双子创造这些内在结构.
structure, and the doubles create these inner structures.
我现在不会一个一个地经过他们。
I will not go through them one by one right now.
实验性筑巢是非常实验性的,
Experimental nesting is very experimental,
暂时关掉 你也可以穿这个
so turn it off for now. You can also have it on.
它需要稍长一点的时间,并且会做多边形的筑巢.
It takes a little bit longer, and it does polygonal nesting.
如果你知道不同种类的巢穴,它不会做一个非常聪明的巢穴.
If you know different types of nesting, it does not do a very smart nesting.
我需要把筑巢算法纳入其中
I need to incorporate a nesting algorithm into it.
而它只做多边形 筑巢为大
And it only does the polygonal nesting for the big
二三十个部分,现在。
20 or 30 parts for now.
这是床单大小。 所以你在这里选择工作表大小,
And this is the sheet size. So you select the sheet size here,
你给一个比值 以免它进入模型的边缘。
and you give a margin so that it does not go to the edge of the model.
然后你选择
And then you choose
部分间距,那么,如果您要
part spacing, so what will be the distance between the parts if you're going to
允许
allow
90度旋转. 如果你是用粗纸板 我建议你
90-degree rotations. If you're using corrugated cardboard, I would suggest you
不允许它这样, 腐蚀是相同的方向, 然后它不
to not allow it so that corrugations are in the same direction, and then it doesn't
听着
look
尴尬。 当你准备好了,你可以开始产生切片,
awkward. And when you're ready, you can start generating slices,
然后它产生切片。 你可以在工作表的布局中看到它。
and then it generates the slices. And you can see it in the sheet layout.
当你完成后,
And when you're done,
所以上面写着:"适合安全布局". 就像我说的,它有很多
so it says, "Fit safe layout." As I said, it has a lot of
间隙间.
space in between now.
不过是的 这是现在它做什么。
But yeah. This is for now what it does.
如果你选择实验
And if you choose the experimental
筑巢,它会把最大的30个部分 一起更好,然后它也会
nesting, it will nest the biggest 30 parts together better, and then it will also
开始使用这些中间部分。
start using these in-between parts.
等你准备好了 你可以去出口了
And when you're ready, you can go to export.
您也可以导出
You can export either
所有床单,只有这张床单,或者只有一张
all the sheets, only this sheet, or only one slice.
你可以在这里同时进行DXF和SVG输出.
And you can do both DXF and SVG exports here.
现在
And then now,
一旦你下载这个,
once you download this,
让我们做一个工作表下载。
let's do a sheet download.
这是... 或者说
This is... Or
这个比较容易看 所以这个SVG已经准备好了
it's easier to show this one. So this SVG is ready to be
用于你选择的激光切割器。
used at a laser cutter of your choosing.
还有别的问题吗?
Any other questions?
一个快速的。 里面的绿色轮廓 只是为了显示
A quick one. The green outline that's on the inside, that's just to show where the
相邻部分是...
adjacent part is-
没错
Exactly
胶着的? 对
... glued? Yep.
对 刻经行. 我想加入它们,让你知道 在哪里需要胶水
Yeah. Engraving lines. I wanted to add them so that you know where you need to glue
接下来的部分。
the next part.
对 这太酷了
Yeah. This is so cool.
对 那又怎样?
Yeah. So what
下一个是
comes next is
明显地增加了更多的特征。 一个是射线切片 还有组装预览
obviously add more features. One is radial slicing and also assembly preview,
调试并解决相互冲突的要求,这意味着当你做一个时
debugging and resolving conflicting requirements, which means that when you do one
执行,通常在其他执行中造成问题,以前
implementation, it usually creates problems in other implementations, previous
执行,所以你需要
implementations, so you need to
一起测试各种特征
go through, test it with various features together.
因此,我需要用更多的用户和模型验证它,以确保这是
So I need to validate it with more users and models to make sure that this is
真的很可靠,你觉得呢? 每一次测试,我都能看到更多
really reliable. And with every test, I can see more
错误并纠正它们。 现在,GitHub计划, 因为我还在做它,
bugs and correct them. Now, the GitHub project, because I'm still working on it,
这是私人的,但想法是把它公之于众 开源以便其他
it's private, but the idea is to make it public and open source so that other
人们可以
people can
改进它,检查它。 但是,如果他们不想使用
improve it, inspect it. But also, if they don't want to use a
网络应用程序用来使用,像Vercel,然后他们可以下载并在当地使用.
web app to use it, like Vercel, then they can download it and use it locally.
上面加上一个基于 LLM 的设计助理 在那里你可以聊天
And maybe to add an LLM-based design assistant on top of this, where you can chat
你用四毫米胶合板 来创造华夫饼结构
and you identify, you say, "Create a waffle structure with four-millimeter plywood
并准备它
and prepare it for
600至400毫米激光切割板". 所以也许可以执行
600 to 400 millimeter laser cutting sheet." So maybe to implement
这样基于 LLM 的设计器系统就可以解释您
this so the LLM-based designer system can interpret your
对话语言并将其解释为
conversational language and interpret it as the parameters of the
应用
app.
呜 很多问题
Oop. Lot of questions.
对
Yes.
顿 对 所以,有一个怀疑 你已经清除了, 预览是一个新的
Hi. Yes. So one doubt you already cleared, that preview is a new
您将添加的即将到来的特性 。
upcoming feature that you will be adding.
对
Mm-hmm.
但我在右侧面板上的一些切片
But some of my slices on the right side panel are
带小琥珀警告符号给我看看
showing me with small amber warning symbols.
对
Mm-hmm.
我认为这些片子没有产生, 因为片面预览中,它只是显示
And I think those slices are not generated, because in slice preview, it just shows
我就像一个矩形。
me like a rectangle.
我们如何解决这个问题? 我可以分享我的屏幕吗?
How do we resolve that? Can I share my screen?
分享这个
Share it.
对
Yeah.
摆
Okay.
你能看见吗?
Can you see this?
对
Yeah.
所以这个警示牌...
So this warning sign-
对
Mm-hmm
这是它展示的切片预览。
... and this is the slice preview it is showing.
对
Mm-hmm.
如果您点击其他切片, 它显示正确 。
If you click on other slices, it is showing correctly.
对
Yeah.
但这是...
But this is-
好吧,这是实际上 零件可以打印或激光切割,但它
Okay, this is actually the parts can be printed or laser cut, but it
因为
is because
标签高度太大, 无法打印标签或刻上标签
the label height is too big that you cannot print a label on it or engrave a label
交给我
on it.
所以说...
So-
哦,没关系。
Oh, okay.
是的,对不起。
Yeah, sorry.
所以如果你减少... 我会尝试展示它。
So if you decrease the... Oop. I will try to show it.
是的,如果你降低标签高度这里,
Yeah, if you decrease the label height here,
你也许可以
you might be able to
把这个弄掉
get rid of this
警告标志。 这也是,这块太小了。
warning sign. It is also that the piece is too small.
摆
Okay.
对 那也可能意味着
Yeah. Then it might also mean that the
上一层雕刻和下一层雕刻不能是
previous layer engraving and the, or the next layer engraving cannot be
已经做了。
made.
哦,没关系。
Oh, okay.
对
Yeah.
当然 是的,这是。
Yeah, sure. Yeah, it is that.
我猜它们还是太小了
I guess they are still too small pieces.
对
Yeah.
但这是... 你能上去一点吗? 我们能看看你的...
But this is... Can you go up a little bit? Can we see your...
是的,这是一个非常小的东西了。
Yeah, it's a very small object now.
这是100 -
It's 100-
是啊,所以这是...
Yeah, so this is-
如果你往左边看...
If you look to the left-
对
Mm-hmm
...你看见...
... you see that the-
这是小的。 对
It is small. Yeah
……你的模型只有十厘米，却要把它切开。
... the size of your object is only the 10 centimeters, and you're trying to cut it
到小块。
to smaller pieces.
摆 我理解,我懂你说什么 摆
Okay. I understand. Okay.
对 故曰因缘.
Yeah. So it's because of that.
摆 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
对
Yeah.
西尔维娅呢?
And Silvia?
没错
I am.
所以,首先,谢谢你,阿斯利。 我对数字设计知之甚少,但这个
So first of all, thank you, Asli. I know very little about digital design, but this
看起来不错,所以...
looked impressive, so
库多斯从我这边。 让人印象深刻
kudos from my side. Totally impressed.
所以,就我的情况而言,我做了
So, in my case, I did the
我通过Blender的多个物体。 它给了我0 -0的数据。
manifold of my object through Blender. It gave me the zero-zero data.
但是,当进口时
But still, when importing
并试图用同样的参数切开它, 它告诉我
and trying to slicing it with the same parameter that you had, it tells me that
这不是多重的。
it's not manifold.
是吗?
Hmm.
那个
The
STL需要进一步调查.
STL needs to be further investigated.
也许在Blender没有多重
Maybe it was not manifold in Blender.
这么说
So
我在Blender的数位。
I manifold in Blender.
它不是紧水的。
It was not watertight.
你说什么?
Sorry?
防水吗?
Watertight?
哦,嗯,我不知道,我说不通。 防水吗?
Oh, well, I don't know. Watertight?
不过是的
But yes,
多重但又不水密 我不知道.
manifolded but not watertight. I don't know.
所以,我用Blender的倍数, 但它告诉我通过程序
So anyway, so I manifold it in Blender, but it's telling me through the program
无法切除,
that is not manifolded and cannot slice it.
对
Mm-hmm.
是吗?
Hmm.
我会尝试一些不同的东西。
I'll try with something different.
对
Yeah.
老实说,我知道如何在犀牛比Blender更容易解决
I know how to solve it in Rhino easier than Blender, to be honest.
我还有...
I have more-
对
Oh, yeah
……
...
更能控制犀牛, 但我不能回答,说实话,在
more control over Rhino, but so I won't be able to answer that, honestly, in
布莱德
Blender.
摆 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
对
Yeah.
还有问题吗?
Any more questions?
对不起 这与教程无关 但你说在开始的时候
I'm sorry. It's not about the tutorial, but you said, in the beginning,
你会
you're going to
将链接设置为教程, 这样我们就可以跟踪到最后
put the link for a tutorial, so we can follow through in the end just to make sure
我们什么都有
we have everything.
米罗板上有一条线索
There is a link in the Miro board-
还好
Okay
她现在为Blender准备了
... she had for the Blender now.
对 谢谢你 安娜塔西亚
Oh, yeah. Oh, thank you, Anastasia.
我在想这个"缩放"的教程, 但是是的,为Blender
I was thinking this Zoom tutorial, but yes, for the Blender
教程,在米罗板上有一个链接和一个YouTube视频.
tutorial, there is a link on the Miro board with a YouTube video.
缩放会作为视频还是...
Will the Zoom be available as a video or-
对
Yeah
笔记? 哦,伟大的。
... notes? Oh, great.
是的,但我们希望它被用于个人 学习,而不是
Yes, but we would like that it is used for personal use to learn and not to
为:
be
在一个有200名学生的课堂上传播。
transmitted in a classroom of 200 students without credits.
当然可以
Sure, of course.
好吗?
Okay?
我找不到Blender教程的链接 那个...
I'm not really finding the link for the Blender tutorial. Is the...
不,没有。
No, there's none.
你现在在米罗板上吗?
Are you on Miro board right now?
米罗? 是的,我有这个。 对
Miro? Yeah, I have this up. Yeah.
在米罗板上
So here in the Miro board,
这是放大的部分, 如果你在这里,
this is the zoomed-out part, and if you go in here,
如何在 Blender 中切割一个模型。
how to cut a model in Blender.
这是一个教程。
This is a tutorial.
你看到了吗,丽塔?
Do you see it now, Rita?
没有 对不起
Not really. Sorry.
你看到我的屏幕了吗?
Do you see my screen now?
是的,我在看你的屏幕。
Yeah, I'm seeing your screen.
摆 你需要放大到设计, 在第二阶段
Okay. You need to zoom into the design, in the second phase of the
这是YouTube的视频。
design, where we do modifications, and this is a YouTube video.
你需要点击它。
You need to click it.
哦,我必须放大。 对
Oh, I have to zoom in. Yeah.
好吗?
Okay?
在设计部分?
In the design part?
对 在设计中。
Yes. Under design.
是啊,在设计。
Yeah, under design.
还有
And
三维模型修改.
3D model modification.
这里。
Here.
你看着它,我会看着聊天。
While you look at it, I will look at the chat.
阿斯利,你要我们给你一些反馈吗?
Asli, would you like us to provide you some feedback about this
教程或经验, 或者你想得到什么反馈?
tutorial or the experience, or what feedback would you like?
对 谢谢 因为我们现在在打结
Yes. Thank you. Because we're tying the ends now.
It会终. 所以,首先,谢谢你的加入。
It's the end of the session. So first of all, thank you for joining.
我们和AI订了位子 所以...
And it was nice because we have our reservations with AI, so it's...
还有
And
所以我总是喜欢用它有意义 和我在控制。
so I always like to use it meaningfully and as much as I'm in control
就像我不会忘记我的人性 和人类的创造力和理解
and as much as I don't forget my humanity and my human creativity and understanding
我的限制,理解AI的
my limitations, understanding AI's
而不是抛弃我所有的一切
limitations, and working together collaboratively, rather than dumping all my
思考过程,或
thought process to it, or
或要求它创造奇迹,因为。
getting all my feedback from it, or asking it to generate miracles for it, because
它不能做到这一点。 所以说...
it cannot do it. So-
所以,这就是我想做的。 所以我希望你先负责任地使用人工智能
So that's what I'd like to do. So I would like you to use AI responsibly first.
是的,我同意这样
Yeah, I agree that
为创造者解密AI 以及它能做什么和做什么
it's really important to demystify AI for creators and what it can do and what it
以及我们仍然需要做的事情。
cannot do, and what we still need to do.
所以,首先,如果你可以 去米罗板和分享
So first of all, if you can go to the Miro board and share
你做过的事
what you have done
和我在这里。 之后你也可以做,但可以看见它
with me here. You can also do it afterwards, but it would be cool to see it
在这里。
here.
想法,你和Gemini产生的东西, 如果你可以放一些照片在这里
The ideation, so what you generated with Gemini, if you can put some photos here
正在设计中。 如果你可以把一些照片从,或
under design. If you can put some photos from, or
您的截图
screenshots from your
Tripo 模型,以及
tripod models, and also
伪造
fabrication
界面截图, 这将很好。
interface screenshots, that would be nice.
还有
And
我想读一些有趣的东西 如果你可以把你的
there is something interesting that I would like to read, and if you can put your
在这里思考和思考, 这将是很好的。
thoughts and reflections in here, that would be also nice.
作为最后的要求,
And as a last request,
有培训后调查, 如果我可以请您填写,
there is the post-training survey that if I may ask you to fill in,
我也会分享
that I will also share the
与您联系
link with you here on
缩放 哦,对不起,不是信号。
Zoom. Oh, sorry, not Signal.
我的缩放呢? 是的,在聊天时。 那我会的
But where's my Zoom? Yes, in chat. Then I will be
能够
able to
也为您提供完成此教程的开放徽章
also provide you with an open badge of completing this tutorial
之后会的 这么说
afterwards. So
如果你做了前期调查 如果你做了后期调查 我可以
if you have done the pre-survey and if you have done the post-survey, I can make
你的名字和邮件,然后我可以给你 打开的徽章到你的电子邮件
your names and emails and then I can send you the open badge to your emails with
那个
that.
对 但我们可以
And yeah. But we can
谈谈
talk about
你对此的看法,你如何体验AI.
what you think about this, how you experience AI.
你也像我一样有AI焦虑症吗?
Do you also have AI anxiety like I do?
因为这是我的工作,也是我现在所看到的,所以我
Because that's my work and that's also what I see everywhere now, so I'm
想知道你的想法吗?
curious to hear about your thoughts as well.
我可以说点什么
Well, I can say something.
是的,请。
Yes, please.
我当然担心AI的使用.
I'm concerned about the use of AI, of course.
对
Mm-hmm.
利用地球上的大量资源
Using a lot of resources on Earth and
它会如何改变所有事物的视角 一个坏的方式,也许在一个
how it's going to change the perspective of everything in a bad way, maybe in a
阴道.
negative way.
接手 我们还得用我们的大脑,对不对?
Taking over. We also have to use our brains still, right?
对
Mm-hmm.
对 当然,我们听到了很多关于所有这些服务中心,等等。
So, yeah. And of course, we hear a lot about all these service centers, et cetera.
最后一点,请。 对
The last point, please. Yeah.
我们也听到很多关于它有多少 用于生成和所有
We also hear a lot about how much it uses for generating and all
这个信息输入 你必须放进去,是的。
this information input you have to put in it, and yeah.
我觉得有点可怕,我不得不说
I think it's a bit scary, I have to say.
и種
I agree.
我认为这是一个非常常见的反应,但
I think that's a very common reaction, but
我今尚不甚拥护.
I don't have a lot of support for this yet.
但我相信当技术推出时 技术是中立的
But my belief is that technology, when it rolls out, is somewhat neutral,
由我们来决定如何部署 如何使用
and it's up to us to decide how it gets deployed and how it gets used.
不幸的是,资本主义
Unfortunately, capitalism
通常倾向于改变事物。 它倾向于去人性化或去技能
usually tends to shift things. It tends to dehumanize technologies or de-skill
人们 但我是现在这个小集体的一员
people. But I'm part of a little collective that is right now
正在工作
working
帮助人们理解AI可以用来
on workshops just like this one to help people understand that AI can be used to
也有好处 就因为我这样的人被它取代了
great benefit as well. To the extent that it's displacing people like me
我是一个软件工程师。 以致于有人从
from-- I was a software engineer. To the extent that it's displacing people from
有些工作,我想它正在为其他工作提供令人难以置信的新机会。
some jobs, I think it's opening incredible new opportunities in other jobs.
我也算是个科技的业余历史学家 如果你看看
I'm also sort of an amateur historian of science and technology, and if you look
回到蒸汽时代 每次发生破坏
back, going all the way back to the Steam Age, every time there was a disruptive
技术的出现, 有很多担心 如何取代它
technology that came out, there was a lot of concern about how displacing it would
将。
be.
我们不一定能预测赢家和输家, 但重要的是开放
We can't necessarily predict the winners and losers, but it's important to be open
以变化而能随其转.
to the change and to be able to roll with it.
还有
And
阿斯利,我认为这完全是正确的 方法来设定它,是人类必须
Asli, I think this is exactly the right way to frame it, is that the human has to
在迭代的每个阶段都保持循环
remain in the loop at every stage in the iteration and really
了解兜帽底下发生了什么
understand sort of what's going on under the hood.
我想你说得对 是为了带回你的私事
And I think you're exactly right. It's to bring your personal
专门技能、知识和背景 影响一个对你很重要的问题
expertise and knowledge and context to bear on a problem that's important to you to
解决,并使用AI 不作为老板,而是作为助手。
solve, and using the AI not as the boss, but as the assistant.
且如所见,有时不为太明.
And as you can see, sometimes it's not too bright.
但是它已经知道很多有趣的事了
But it already knows ahead of time a lot of really interesting
上下文。 我想如果你把它当作镜子 来反射你自己的
context. And I think if you use it as kind of a mirror to reflect back your own
理智和偏见,
sensibilities and your own biases,
从某种意义上说,大赦国际可以帮助我们更好地理解成为人类意味着什么。
that in a sense, AI can help us understand better what it means to be human.
对
Yeah.
我两分钱
My two cents.
谢谢你,克里。 и種 仅与
Thank you, Kerry. I agree. Only with
一个与你所说的话的开始有关的评论。
one comment that is related to the very beginning of what you said.
每一个技术都是中性的
It's every technology born neutral.
我觉得AI不是这样的,因为它使用了数据
I think that is not true with AI because it used datas
通常占多数的
of people that are usually mostly represented on
互联网。 所以它不是中立的开始。
internet. So it does not start neutrally.
所以它用
So it uses
英语作为第一语言, 以及那里的大部分数据
English as its first language, and most data out there
也用英语,它属于某些
is also in English, and it belongs to certain
文化和某些人。 所以,这不是出生,或者当它告诉
cultures and certain people. So this was not born, or when it told
从一开始它就一直保持中立
something back at us, it was never neutral from the beginning.
但除此之外,我同意需要讨论,而且需要,
But apart from that, I agree that it needs to be discussed, and it needs to be,
限制和需要
within these kind of contexts, its limits and needs to be
探索,也需要有点像, 我们在哪里结束?
explored, and also needs to be a little bit like, where do we end?
AI是从哪里开始的或任何其他技术?
Where does AI start or any other technology start?
我们需要进一步探讨这个问题,并看到与我们的合作。
We need to explore that further and see in kind of collaborations we can see with
这个 还有
it. And
我丈夫是软件工程师 他看到什么后也感到很羞愧
my husband is a software engineer, and he was also very mortified when he saw what
我却不知所措
I was able to do without knowing much.
我知道一点
I know a little bit
编程。 所以,正如我所说,我是一个计算设计师, 所以我不从
programming. So as I said, I'm a computational designer, so I don't start with
但我显然也做不了这么多编码
blank slate, but I also cannot do this much of coding, obviously.
但希望它不会取代工作, 我们需要向前看
But hopefully it will not replace the jobs, and we need to move towards looking
如何减轻其短期和长期影响
into how we can mitigate short-term and long-term impacts of it
在社会以及就业保障方面。
in the society as well in terms of job security, too.
但了解它肯定不会伤害我们, 因为那样它就能赋予我们作为
But definitely it doesn't hurt to learn about it, because then it empowers us as
不错
well.
我很抱歉,但我错过了你最初说的大部分话 所以我非常想
I'm very sorry, but I missed most of what you said initially, so I would very much
喜欢后续跟进。
like to follow up after.
对 让我们做。
Yeah. Let's do.
摆 没关系 不错
Okay. That's fine. Great.
湿婆呢?
And Shiva?
顿
Hi.
首先,这是对三维模型的一次伟大的探索
So first of all, this was a great exploration in 3D models and
gen AI用来使用.
gen AI to use it.
我也一样
I'm also quite
在使用AI时保留。
reserved when it comes to use of AI.
这也许是我一个月里使用最多的人工智能
This might be the most amount of AI used in a month for me.
不过
But
是的,这是一次伟大的演示 如何使用AI而不离开
yeah, this was, again, a great demonstration of how to use AI without leaving the
司机的座位,所以说。 没错
driver's seat, so to speak. So yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you for that
我还要补充一点,现在,
I would also like to add that nowadays,
至少我个人的看法是
at least my personal perspective is that
人类需要更多技能
what the humans need to develop more are skills
比如政策 社会学 人类学 这样你就可以
like policy, sociology, anthropology, so that you can
例如,实际上为AI写规则.
actually, for example, write the rules for the AI.
这些技能是更需要的技能。
These kind of skills are skills that they are going to be more needed.
и種 柔软的技能是... 怎么样
I agree. Soft skills will be... And how to
更深入地探索人类的一面
find out our human side more, or figure out, explore our human side more.
是啊,所有这些事情的历史,
Yeah, the history of all of those things,
它们对于在下列地点推动大赦国际至关重要:
they are very essential for being able to drive the AI where
它应该。
it should.
对
Mm-hmm.
梅丽莎?
Melissa?
对 顿
Yes. Hi.
我想告诉你一件事,因为
I want to tell you something, because
我们班上看到的一切
all we see in this class,
有位老师告诉我
come to me once a teacher told us that
AI要取代我们成为雕塑家
AI was going to replace us to the sculptors.
但我认为这是艺术家之间的合作
But I think it's a work collaborate between the artist
和AI,现在我们可以创建独特的作品。
and the AI, now we can create unique pieces.
我觉得
And I think
其他人,就像我一样
the people in other place, like my
因为我来自阿亚库乔
city, because I am from Ayacucho,
我们必须
we must
失去这些新技术的恐惧,思考
lose the scary about these new technologies and think
对电脑来说很可怕
about the computer and was scary for the
人们不知道使用。
people doesn't know about the use.
但现在它是很多作品和艺术家的补充
But now it's a complement for a lot of works and the artists
像我一样,它是非常
like me, it's at all very
现在很重要。
important now.
上课后,我有很多想法
After this class, I have a lot of ideas
为工作。 且道个甚么. 谢谢
for work. And that's all. Thank you.
我很高兴听到这个,梅丽莎。
I'm happy to hear that, Melissa.
我真的很高兴听到这个, 因为事实上这是我们的意图, 介绍
I'm really happy to hear that because that was actually our intention, to introduce
你来这
you to this
有点世界,不是觉得我们迷失了,而是觉得
world a little bit, not to feel ourselves lost, but to
看我们如何
see how we can
如果可能,开辟新的机会。
open up new opportunities if possible.
如果这对我们没有好处 那也是公平的
And if it's not something for us, that's also fair.
一旦我们知道了,我们也可以继续前进。 我们不需要用它。
Once we know, we can also move on. We don't need to use it.
我们不需要参与其中。 但我们需要知道能够作出决定。
We don't need to be part of it. But we need to know to be able to decide.
梅丽莎 没人会取代
Well, Melissa, nobody will replace the
恢复你正在做的 Stucco 石膏, 与石膏
restoration that you are doing with the stucco plastering, with the plastering of
修复这座建筑。 我认为它不会被AI取代.
the rehabilitation of this building. I don't think that it will be replaced by AI.
没有 我们还做了另一个项目。
No. We also do another project as well.
对
Yes.
对 和工匠们在一起 他们甚至...
Yeah. It's with craft people. They even-
所以用你的手来做事情
So do things with your hands
……
...
我们和工匠一起工作
we work with craft people.
没错
Exactly.
他们说AI能做的太多了 他们无法创造蕾丝作品
And they say that there's so much that AI can do, and they cannot create lace work,
或者他们不能恢复 或者他们不能...
or they cannot do restoration, or they cannot...
有些东西是非常人性的。 对
There are these things that are very human. Yeah.
什么事,茱莉亚?
Yes, Julia?
当你在谈论AI和修复建筑物时,
As you were talking about AI and restoration of buildings,
我们的教授工作, 他正在做一个项目,他做
our professor at work, he's working on a project where he does
修复带有机器人的建筑物,这是用AI编程的.
restoration of buildings with robots, which is programmed with AI.
所以我不会说这不会改变,或
So, I would not say that this won't change, or
我认为有这么多的要点, 这么多的工作,我们现在无法想象
I think there are so many points, so many jobs where we now can't imagine that
AI和机器人以及新技术能够
AI and robots and new technologies are able to
改变那些工作。 但我觉得没什么
change those jobs. But I think nothing is
目前无法想象
unimaginable at the moment.
我尽量不走这些长度。
I try not to go to those lengths yet.
我有点害怕在那一刻想,想
It kind of scares me to think about that at that moment, to think
难以想象
the unimaginable.
我不知道.
I don't know. I
试着让自己相信可能性
try to ground myself on the possibilities.
是的,但我同意这一点
Yeah, but I agree that
几周前,我一直担心 我们要去哪里,会发生什么
a few weeks ago, I had an anxiety about where we are going, what's going to happen
十年内? 我们10年后还会在附近吗? 却甚难.
in 10 years? Are we going to be around still in 10 years? But it's so hard.
但我同意安娜塔西亚的观点 我们需要
But I agree with Anastasia point that we need
明确政策
clear policy around
我们如何处理它 如何特别大的技术处理它。
how we handle it and how especially big tech handles it.
对
Yes,
诺埃尔? 或者茱莉亚,你还有更多的分数 你想分享还是...
Noel? Or Julia, did you have more points that you want to share or...
对
Yeah.
再次感谢你主持这次辅导
Once again, thank you for conducting this tutorial.
我基本上是一个电子工程师 做电路设计, 我听说过
I'm basically an electronics engineer who do circuit designing, and I have heard
关于三维模特很多次,很多年, 但我还没有尝试
about 3D modeling many times, many years, but I haven't tried
在这个问题上。 这让我更洞察力
on this subject. But this gave me more insight
做更多的工作,因为,作为一个电子工程师, 我做原型,但
to work on more because, as a electronics engineer, I do prototyping, but
大部分时候我用
mostly I use
我原型的外壳 但这给了我更多的洞察力。
off-the-shelf enclosures for my prototyping. But this gave me more insight.
它给了我
It gave me
有机会考虑
an opportunity to think about to
使用3D型号,定制型号,
use a 3D model, customized one,
这是很好的。 还有AI上的第二件事
which is good. And the second thing on AI.
是的,AI会推进, 但是在修复点, 几天前,我是
Yeah, AI will advance, but on the restoration point, a few days before I was
恢复一个旧的索尼Hi-Fi系统 AI帮助我寻找旧的
restoring one old Sony Hi-Fi system, and AI helped me on looking on old
图表和修复。 但是,在修复方面,我们
schematics and to fix that. But again, on the restoration part, our
手必须去修复。
hands has to go for the restoration.
AI可以支持我们,但AI不能接手. 对 谢谢 再次感谢你
AI can support us, but AI can't take over. Yeah. Thank you. Thank you once again.
对
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
对
Yeah.
没事吧?
All good?
对 谢谢大家 谢谢
Yes. Thank you, everyone. Thank you.
对
Yeah.
谢谢,娜塔莉。
Thanks, Natalie.
如果你愿意,我再次请你填写表格。
I would, again, ask you to fill in the form if you feel like it.
这对我有很大帮助 你无法想象
It helps me majorly, immensely. You cannot imagine.
但是,感谢大家的加入, 如果你想进一步 谈话,想
But thank you all for joining, and if you want to further the conversation, want to
更了解我们在文艺复兴项目或任何其他项目中做什么
know more about what we do within the Renaissance project or any other projects
在WAW,我给你我的邮件 在这里,所以你可以写信给我,或者我也会
at WAW, I give you my email here, so you can write to me, or I will also
把它放在壁画板上 这样你就能找到我
put it on the mural board so you have where to find me.
对
Yeah.
基本上,邮电训练是一样的,但是...
Basically, the post training is the same, but...
练完之后
After you have done the training.
在你完成课程之后,不是吗?
After you have done the course, no?
对
Yeah.
摆 亦复如是.
Okay. It's the same.
据我所知,这不是那么长。
It's not that lengthy as far as I remember.
摆
Okay.
但是它告诉你 你学到了多少,你学到了什么?
But it tells you how much you learned and did you learn anything?
对
Mm-hmm.
我帮你吗?
Was I helpful to you?
对
Yeah.
不错 谢谢
Great. Thank you.
对 谢谢
Yeah. Thank you.
再见。
Bye.
再见
Bye-bye.
再见。
Bye.